<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE quotations [
  <!ENTITY ccedil "&#231;"> <!-- latin small letter c with cedilla -->
  <!ENTITY eacute "&#233;"> <!-- latin small letter e with acute -->
]>
<?xml-stylesheet href="http://www.amk.ca/qel/qel.css"?>

<quotations xmlns="http://www.amk.ca/qel/"
            xmlns:rdf='http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#'>
  <title>Comic Book Quotations</title>
  <description>Quotations from various comic book titles.</description>
  <editor>A.M. Kuchling</editor>
  <!-- Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike license -->
  <rdf:RDF xmlns="http://web.resource.org/cc/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
    <Work rdf:about="">
       <dc:type rdf:resource="http://purl.org/dc/dcmitype/Text" />
       <license rdf:resource="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/" />
    </Work>

    <License rdf:about="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/">
       <permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Reproduction" />
       <permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Distribution" />
       <requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Notice" />
       <requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Attribution" />
       <permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/DerivativeWorks" />
       <requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/ShareAlike" />
    </License>

    </rdf:RDF>

  <quotation id="q1">
    <p>
      You're a good guy, Doc. You're sensitive and caring and compassionate.
      And if I could, I'd spew in your face.
    </p>
    <source>Cliff Steele in DOOM PATROL #19</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q2">
    <p>
      "Hello, Kay. Isn't it a bit wet to be painting?"
    </p>
    <p>
      "Kay's down in the underground, where there's no rain. You're talking
      to the hangman's beautiful daughter."
    </p>
    <source>Magnus and Kay Challis ("Crazy Jane") in DOOM PATROL #19.</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q3">
    <p>
      I've tried to be like them, I really have. But what happens when you
      just can't be strong anymore? What happens if you're weak? My
      painting's ruined. Everything's gone wrong.
    </p>
    <source>Crazy Jane in DOOM PATROL #19</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q4">
    <p>
      Guy was a human torch, you know? Literally. His hair... everything...
      but he kept on walking. Real slow, like in a bad dream. Before he
      died, he said something weird. I... I got it written down right here.
      "...scissormen... The scissormen!"
    </p>
    <source>A stunned cop in DOOM PATROL #19</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q5">
    <p>
      It begins to rain fish. Mackerel. Herring. Sea bass. Pike. Sturgeon.
      Tench. Plaice. Salmon. From a clear sky. Trout. No cod.
    </p>
    <source>Father McGarry's last sight, in DOOM PATROL #20.</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q6">
    <p>
      "Rain Brain says your voice is like an old black telephone and Black
      Annis told me to tell you that you're the first man she hasn't wanted
      to castrate."
    </p>
    <p>
      "Tell her she'd be too late anyway."
    </p>
    <source>Crazy Jane and Cliff Steele in DOOM PATROL #20.</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q7">
    <p>
      "Thirdly be grimmer as fond brevities."
    </p>
    <p>
      "Eider with alders."
    </p>
    <p>
      "And erethism safer."
    </p>
    <source>Three Scissormen introduce themselves in DOOM PATROL #20</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q8">
    <p>
      In Rome, in Leningrad, in Darwin. "The door flew open, in he ran, the
      great, long, red-legged scissorman."
    </p>
    <source>From DOOM PATROL #20</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q9">
    <p>
      I couldn't think of one clever way to stop this guy, so I just trusted
      to mindless violence.
    </p>
    <source>Cliff Steele in DOOM PATROL #21</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q10">
    <p>
      "Jane? Jane, are you... Oh my God."
    </p>
    <p>
      "There is no God. I killed him."
    </p>
    <source>Cliff Steele meets Black Annis in DOOM PATROL #21.</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q11">
    <p>
      All I want is the answer to one simple question before I run screaming
      back to the bughouse. Is this real or isn't it?
    </p>
    <source>Cliff Steele in DOOM PATROL #21</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q12">
    <p>
      "It might help to consider the Zen koan, 'First there is a mountain,
      then there is no mountain, then there is.'"
    </p>
    <p>
      "Sure. That's really helped to clear things up."
    </p>
    <source>Niles Caulder and Cliff Steele in DOOM PATROL #21</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q13">
    <p>
      Here the skull of a consumptive child becomes part of a great machine
      for calculating the motions of the stars. Here, a yellow bird frets
      within the ribcage of an unjust man.
    </p>
    <source>Welcome to Orqwith, in DOOM PATROL #22</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q14">
    <p>
      You know, all of a sudden I can't think of anything even remotely
      funny to say.
    </p>
    <source>Cliff Steele sees Orqwith, in DOOM PATROL #22</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q15">
    <p>
      Sorry about the writing. Robot fingers, you know?
    </p>
    <source>Cliff Steele in DOOM PATROL #23</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q16">
    <p>
      "You shot your imaginary friends? With what?"
    </p>
    <p>
      "An imaginary gun! What else?"
    </p>
    <source>Josh and Dorothy in DOOM PATROL #25</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q17">
    <p>
      I wish I were an angry shoe, a bodiless balloon. Cut off my covenant
      with God the pain of orthopedic glue.
    </p>
    <source>Darling-Come-Home's song in DOOM PATROL #25</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q18">
    <p>
      "Shouldn't we put Cliff's brain back into the body?"
    </p>
    <p>
      "Later, Joshua. I refuse to perform a delicate operation without
      chocolate."
    </p>
    <source>Josh and Niles Caulder, in DOOM PATROL #34</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q19">
    <p>
      "Where is my gum? I must try to look as normal as possible."
    </p>
    <p>
      "I believe you stuck it onto the side of my head."
    </p>
    <source>Monsieur Mallah and the Brain, in DOOM PATROL #34</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q20">
    <p>
      Chess! I'm tormented by thoughts of strip chess. Pure mind just isn't
      enough, Mallah. I long for a body.
    </p>
    <source>The Brain, in DOOM PATROL #34</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q21">
    <p>
      Instead, you and I became the cornerstones of the Brotherhood of Evil!
      An empire of crime such as I'd dreamed of back in the old school, when
      the other children used to laugh at me because I was a brain in a
      tank.
    </p>
    <source>The Brain, in DOOM PATROL #34</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q22">
    <p>
      I don't think. I just act. You brains are the ones who do all the
      thinking. You ruin it for us bodies.
    </p>
    <source>Cliff's body, in DOOM PATROL #34</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q23">
    <p>
      Kiss me, Mallah! But first... please.. take that gum out of your
      mouth.
    </p>
    <source>The Brain, in DOOM PATROL #34</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q24">
    <p>
      Oh, Venice, Venice, what have you allowed yourself to become? Crushed
      by the weight of your own past, stinking slowly into the waves.
      They've taken away your function, removed you from the present and
      from the future, and turned you into a drug mainlined into the veins
      of history junkies.
    </p>
    <source>??? in DOOM PATROL #50</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q25">
    <p>
      I'm warning you--I have a boiled egg and I know how to use it!
    </p>
    <source>??? in DOOM PATROL #50</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q26">
    <p>
      Now. Take this street to New Mexico.
    </p>
    <source>??? in DOOM PATROL #50</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q27">
    <p>
      The Living Guru! Hip-hop bishop of beat! The cool, gone Daddio of the
      Deva Dimensions!
    </p>
    <source>Grant Morrison goes completely insane in DOOM PATROL #53</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q28">
    <p>
      You could say it all started in Arizona. Twenty-five years ago. On a
      farm.
    </p>
    <source>The narrator, in ENIGMA #1: "The Lizard, The Head, The Enigma"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q29">
    <p>
      It was an ordinary sort of farm in Arizona. The kind of place where
      you'd have sexual relations with your parents and end up shooting
      someone.
    </p>
    <source>The narrator, in ENIGMA #1: "The Lizard, The Head, The Enigma"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q30">
    <p>
      The well was like an old man who'd lost the desire to get dressed in
      the mornings. The well would sit around all day in its pajamas waiting
      for something to happen... Twenty-five years ago something did happen.
    </p>
    <source>The narrator, in ENIGMA #1: "The Lizard, The Head, The Enigma"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q31">
    <p>
      On Tuesdays he also wears the blue socks and the grey underwear and
      counts his bath towels. He has twenty-five bath towels. But how could
      anyone survive with less?
    </p>
    <source>The narrator introduces us to Michael Smith, in ENIGMA #1: "The Lizard, The Head, The Enigma"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q32">
    <p>
      Michael is a tree ape who lost most of his hairs and now has
      nightmares about black horses and cancer. Sometimes he feels like a
      rumor drifting through a world of hard facts. What's the
      <em>point</em> of you, Michael?
    </p>
    <source>The narrator asks a rhetorical question, in ENIGMA #1: "The Lizard, The Head, The Enigma"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q33">
    <p>
      The little mind games he plays, like reciting the dictionary backwards
      from memory, fail to amuse him for long. The walls of the world have
      been torn down and the wind that blows through is cold and
      preposterous.
    </p>
    <source>The Enigma waits in his room, in ENIGMA #1: "The Lizard, The Head, The Enigma"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q34">
    <p>
      He creates a new language, a new grammar, eight cases and five
      genders. This passes twenty minutes. Then it's boredom again...
    </p>
    <source>The Enigma kills time, in ENIGMA #1: "The Lizard, The Head, The Enigma"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q35">
    <p>
      Boredom, ennui, absurdity. His closest, his only friends... It looks
      like there's nothing for him to do but get dressed.
    </p>
    <source>Getting ready, in ENIGMA #1: "The Lizard, The Head, The Enigma"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q36">
    <p>
      He couldn't face Sandra this morning. Crept out without saying
      goodbye. There's a dent on the hood of his car. There's a green lizard
      floating across the road.
    </p>
    <source>Michael's commute is interrupted, in ENIGMA #1: "The Lizard, The Head, The Enigma"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q37">
    <p>
      You see, you're all wrong. My name isn't Brain Eater. I am the Head.
      And I don't simply eat brains. It's something deeper than that.
      Something magical. Something transubstantiational. Excuse me one
      moment while I ... &lt;shlurppp&gt;
    </p>
    <source>The first villain, in ENIGMA #1: "The Lizard, The Head, The Enigma"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q38">
    <p>
      Many primitive [*] peoples believe that if you eat a person's brains,
      you acquire his knowledge.
    </p>
    <p>
      [*] Footnote: A primitive person is one who doesn't drive a car. Cars
      are among the greatest causes of premature deaths of lizards in
      Arizona.
    </p>
    <source>Digressing, in ENIGMA #1: "The Lizard, The Head, The Enigma"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q39">
    <p>
      When the honey of another's life touches my nervous system I could
      almost be sucking on God's little finger.
    </p>
    <source>The Head, in ENIGMA #1: "The Lizard, The Head, The Enigma"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q40">
    <p>
      As soon as Roger saw the costume, his mind assumed the proportions of
      an industrial revolution unaware of the ecological damage it was
      causing.
    </p>
    <source>The origin of the Head, in ENIGMA #1: "The Lizard, The Head, The Enigma"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q41">
    <p>
      His first victim was a priest. Roger's senses were blessed with
      furtive longings and sweet altar wine.
    </p>
    <source>The Head's backstory, in ENIGMA #1: "The Lizard, The Head, The Enigma"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q42">
    <p>
      I am the Head and I demand your shrunken experiences now!
    </p>
    <source>In ENIGMA #1: "The Lizard, The Head, The Enigma"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q43">
    <p>
      What do you think? Which has a better, a more sublimely developed,
      sense of the ridiculous? Life? Or death? Or me? Or Michael Smith?
    </p>
    <source>A rhetorical question, in ENIGMA #1: "The Lizard, The Head, The Enigma"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q44">
    <p>
      If it wasn't for the fact that a monster called the Head was plunging
      a metal pipe up his nose preparatory to sucking his brains out,
      Michael Smith could almost laugh.
    </p>
    <source>Opening sentence of ENIGMA #2: "The Truth"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q45">
    <p>
      At last he's got it. He's got the joke. The joke is life. The
      punchline is that there are so many things he'd like to do with his
      life, now that his life is over. Not much of a joke. Not much of a
      life.
    </p>
    <source>Michael Smith makes his peace, in ENIGMA #2: "The Truth"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q46">
    <p>
      I know who you are, he thinks. You're my old secret pal... You're the
      Enigma, he thinks... And then dies.
    </p>
    <source>The protagonist dies, in ENIGMA #2: "The Truth"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q47">
    <p>
      "But as the papers say, he's caught the public's imagination."
    </p>
    <p>
      "Didn't know they had any."
    </p>
    <source>Cops, in ENIGMA #2: "The Truth"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q48">
    <p>
      He sits quite still for two days, forgetting to move. Remembering the
      previous two days with such precision that it takes fully two days to
      remember them... remembering with such clarity that he forgets for a
      while that this is a memory and not the thing remembered.
    </p>
    <source>The Enigma kills more time, in ENIGMA #2: "The Truth"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q49">
    <p>
      Is this enough? Does this make it worthwhile? Does this make it less
      absurd? With these actions can I recreate the dark and sensible walls
      of an abandoned well?
    </p>
    <source>The Enigma wonders, in ENIGMA #2: "The Truth"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q50">
    <p>
      He took the Head in his arms and looked into the eyes, looking for
      recognition, meaning, something, and seeing only madness and death,
      bashed his head open.
    </p>
    <source>The Enigma recollects, in ENIGMA #2: "The Truth"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q51">
    <p>
      ... lies and half-truths and deceits. Our society is built on them.
      Our churches and schools and politicians deal in them. Your entire
      lives are awash with them.
    </p>
    <source>The Truth, in ENIGMA #2: "The Truth"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q52">
    <p>
      "Who among you can claim to be honest? Who does not lie? You? Do you
      claim to be honest?"
    </p>
    <p>
      "Ahhh, I just work here, sir."
    </p>
    <source>The Truth and a security guard, in ENIGMA #2: "The Truth"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q53">
    <p>
      "If you could step outside..."
    </p>
    <p>
      "There is no outside. There is no inside or outside, no up or down,
      when it comes to the truth."
    </p>
    <source>A security guard and the Truth, in ENIGMA #2: "The Truth"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q54">
    <p>
      For a moment he hesitates, memories stirring. Another life, another
      person. Suntans, lies and half-truths, a wife, a mistress, the
      clandestine clinic for cocaine dependency... A package arriving one
      morning containing a see-through, a brutually honest see-through body
      stocking...
    </p>
    <source>The Truth falters, in ENIGMA #2: "The Truth"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q55">
    <p>
      The Truth fixes the unlucky man with a stare of such dismal honesty
      that the complex layers of lies and illusions on which the man's life
      is based fall away, one by one, leaving in their place all that is
      left once the lies have gone... nothing.
    </p>
    <source>The Truth's modus operandi, in ENIGMA #2: "The Truth"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q56">
    <p>
      Should we say any words? We can't just turn him off like he was a
      microwave or something.
    </p>
    <source>Sandra watches Michael's life support being turned off, in ENIGMA #2: "The Truth"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q57">
    <p>
      Look at me. Look into my eyes. See the bitter truth of your life
      reflected in them. All those lonely nights. All those nasty thoughts.
      You're the actor. <em>You're</em> the one playing a character who is a
      lie!
    </p>
    <source>The Truth kills again, in ENIGMA #2: "The Truth"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q58">
    <p>
      For a second he feels almost solid. Almost as though he were a real
      person in a real world.
    </p>
    <source>The Enigma pauses a moment, in ENIGMA #2: "The Truth"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q59">
    <p>
      The ants scurrying about, busily feeding, fighting, collecting,
      building, dying. The lizards watching the world as though they're
      wise, but they're not wise, just ugly enough to be wise.
    </p>
    <source>Further reflections, in ENIGMA #2: "The Truth"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q60">
    <p>
      It's like the book of Revelations, but funnier. It's like the Last
      Trumpet, but hopelessly out of tune. It's like the perennial battle
      between good and evil but no one can quite work out which is which
      anymore, and most people don't even know what perennial means.
    </p>
    <source>Opening lines of ENIGMA #3: "The Good Boy"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q61">
    <p>
      The Truth has entered the church. He broke in a few hours ago and gave
      a sermon on the kind of truths you won't find in any book. Good, bad,
      or indifferent. Thirty-five believers, ten agnostics and two closet
      Satanists kicked the Eucharist.
    </p>
    <source>The Truth strikes again, in ENIGMA #3: "The Good Boy"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q62">
    <p>
      But look at these others. The Enigmatics, they call themselves. Did
      these apes lose most of their brains when they lost most of their
      hair? They can't wait to leave their parents, then once they've left
      them, can't wait to find new and bigger parents to obey.
    </p>
    <source>The Enigma spawns a cult, in ENIGMA #3: "The Good Boy"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q63">
    <p>
      My own characters have come to life to get me, I thought. I should
      have been nicer to them.
    </p>
    <source>Titus Bird, in ENIGMA #3: "The Good Boy"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q64">
    <p>
      Dad died in the last big earthquake to hit Pacific. It was like, after
      that, Mom was scared of anything chaotic in our lives. Like everything
      was on the edge of collapsing, getting sucked into an earthquake of
      chaos.
    </p>
    <source>Michael talks about his parents, in ENIGMA #3: "The Good Boy"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q65">
    <p>
      "Someone, I think John Cage, said that life without order was chaos,
      but order without life was death."
    </p>
    <p>
      "Who's John Cage?"
    </p>
    <p>
      "It doesn't matter."
    </p>
    <source>Titus and Michael, in ENIGMA #3: "The Good Boy"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q66">
    <p>
      Hey, Michael, you really don't want to go in there. No, really you
      don't. The Truth hurts, you know...
    </p>
    <source>Closing lines of ENIGMA #3: "The Good Boy"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q67">
    <p>
      "Are you ready for me? Are you ready for my indifference? For my
      abysmal disinterest? Are you ready to have the lies and conceits of
      your life peeled away like so many layers of skin? Are you ready for
      the truth?"
    </p>
    <p>
      "Ahhh... No, I... I don't really think I am..."
    </p>
    <source>The Truth and Michael Smith, in ENIGMA #4: "And Then What?"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q68">
    <p>
      Too bad. The truth is a rude guest. The truth doesn't knock on the
      door and wait to be asked in.
    </p>
    <source>The Truth, in ENIGMA #4: "And Then What?"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q69">
    <p>
      Look into my eyes. You will see the dull horror of your childhood and
      we will begin to dissect this pointless obsession of yours.
    </p>
    <source>The Truth, in ENIGMA #4: "And Then What?"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q70">
    <p>
      When he opens his eyes he finds himself in a nightmare world
      surrounded by nightmare creatures with grotesque ovoid heads and
      wildly flapping limbs. Michael tells the policemen he remembers
      nothing.
    </p>
    <source>Aftermath, in ENIGMA #4: "And Then What?"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q71">
    <p>
      Exactly the Truth is being carted out, to the cheers of the crowd, who
      obviously fail to see the irony of the Truth dying in a church.
      Actually, I fail to see the irony in that too, but who cares what I
      think? I mean, do I really care what you think? Who are you anyway? I
      mean, are you following any of this?
    </p>
    <source>The narrator gets tetchy, in ENIGMA #4: "And Then What?"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q72">
    <p>
      Someone has broken into his house and completely rearranged the
      furniture. And as he looks at the room, now so grotesquely unfamiliar,
      it's as though something breaks into John's head, and completely
      rearranges the furniture there.
    </p>
    <source>John Cade's doom, in ENIGMA #4: "And Then What?"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q73">
    <p>
      "TV and papers are full of it. They creep into homes and rearrange the
      furniture."
    </p>
    <p>
      "My God! The monsters!"
    </p>
    <source>Titus and Michael discuss the Interior League, in ENIGMA #4: "And Then What?"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q74">
    <p>
      It seems they rearrange the furniture in such a way that somehow, God
      knows how, it drives at least one member of the household crazy. Like
      the furniture arranged in this pattern is a key that unlocks the
      mind...
    </p>
    <source>Titus explains the Interior League, in ENIGMA #4: "And Then What?"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q75">
    <p>
      Like so many others who have abandoned jobs, families, commitments;
      who chucked in the whole caboodle, torn up their past lives and all
      they'd thought important to seek out Envelope Girl. All captivated by
      her strong manila arms, her lovely gumminess, the heady allure of her
      zip code.
    </p>
    <source>An aging judge's description, in ENIGMA #4: "And Then What?"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q76">
    <p>
      Returned to his place, he sits quite still, pretending he doesn't
      exist, which is a harder game than you might imagine.
    </p>
    <source>The Enigma kills yet more time, in ENIGMA #4: "And Then What?"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q77">
    <p>
      Oh great. Charlie Manson is on my side. Things are really looking up.
    </p>
    <source>Titus Bird, in ENIGMA #4: "And Then What?"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q78">
    <p>
      You know what impresses me about you? Your ability to be as pathetic
      as you are and not want to kill yourself. If I were you, I'd
      <em>have</em> to kill myself.
    </p>
    <source>The Enigma talks to the rich cat, in ENIGMA #4: "And Then What?"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q79">
    <p>
      What does it mean, huh? What does it mean when those kids die so...
      pointlessly? It doesn't mean anything, does it? That's the scary part.
      If it meant something, you could handle it, but it doesn't.
    </p>
    <source>Titus Bird, in ENIGMA #4: "And Then What?"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q80">
    <p>
      Look, they're carrying the corpses away, ho hum.
    </p>
    <source>Opening line of ENIGMA #5: "Lizards and Ghosts"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q81">
    <p>
      Do I sound detached? Indifferent? I'm not, believe me. I'll tell you a
      secret: I'm not a distant narrator, aloof from the action of this
      story... I'm a part of this story.
    </p>
    <source>The narrator drops a hint, in ENIGMA #5: "Lizards and Ghosts"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q82">
    <p>
      It's the following day and two more houses have been redecorated by
      the Interior League. Five people dead.
    </p>
    <source>Events continue to flow, in ENIGMA #5: "Lizards and Ghosts"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q83">
    <p>
      But somehow lizards are connected to all this. They're a constant
      theme.
    </p>
    <source>Michael Smith, in ENIGMA #5: "Lizards and Ghosts"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q84">
    <p>
      What are we doing in this suburban living room? And look at that
      furniture, for God's sake!
    </p>
    <source>The narrator comments on decor, in ENIGMA #5: "Lizards and Ghosts"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q85">
    <p>
      The eyes burn with all the wet violence of the young and all the dry
      malevolence of the old. ... This creature will play a big part in our
      story, you wait.
    </p>
    <source>Foreshadowing, in ENIGMA #5: "Lizards and Ghosts"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q86">
    <p>
      Molesters and foul abusers of comfy chairs and imitation Edwardian
      sideboards, deflowerers of teak coffee tables and meek landscape
      paintings and ...
    </p>
    <source>The Interior League described, in ENIGMA #5: "Lizards and Ghosts"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q87">
    <p>
      This of course is nothing like the comic book Enigma. This is real
      life, or as real as your life gets, anyway.
    </p>
    <source>Violence, in ENIGMA #5: "Lizards and Ghosts"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q88">
    <p>
      Of course I'm here. I've always been here, there, and everywhere.
    </p>
    <source>Envelope Girl sounds rather Kosh-like, in ENIGMA #5: "Lizards and Ghosts"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q89">
    <p>
      My mother laid flowers on the ground above here. Seagulls flew off
      with them, before the crappy little makeshift service was even
      finished. Everything was against us. My poor old dad. The ground
      swallowed him and then the sky stole his flowers. Poor old dad.
    </p>
    <source>Michael Smith in the tomb, in ENIGMA #6: "The End of The World"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q90">
    <p>
      I lost my Enigma comics too. They were buried with him and I used to
      imagine him like an Egyptian pharaoh, buried with what he needed for
      the afterlife, reading <cite>The Enigma</cite> for all eternity.
    </p>
    <source>Michael Smith, in ENIGMA #6: "The End of The World"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q91">
    <p>
      "I'm whoever you want me to be."
    </p>
    <p>
      "No, sorry. That's the kind of tacky, bogus line that Titus used to
      come up with. It works okay on the page but just doesn't sound real
      when it's spoken."
    </p>
    <source>The Enigma and Michael, in ENIGMA #6: "The End of The World"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q92">
    <p>
      People move in and out of other people's lives, and no one ever knows
      exactly what other people are thinking. In this way we are all alone.
      But I am more alone than most.
    </p>
    <source>The narrator, in ENIGMA #7: "Sex in Arizona"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q93">
    <p>
      He had a charming lightness of touch as he transfixed the young
      doctor, neatly stripped him, and prepared to devour him, smelly toes
      first. Of course they hadn't told him that he wasn't allowed to eat
      the doctors: they'd just arrogantly presumed he wouldn't.
    </p>
    <source>Opening lines of ENIGMA #8: "Queer"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q94">
    <p>
      I think we should just be silent for one moment here, and contemplate
      this waste of reptilian life. Excuse me, are you still there? I
      haven't lost you yet, have I?
    </p>
    <source>The narrator is uncharacteristically moved, in ENIGMA #8: "Queer"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q95">
    <p>
      It's my belief that if you cut into a thing deeply enough; if your
      incisions are precise and persistent and conducted methodically, then
      you may reveal not only that thing's inner workings, but also the
      <em>meaning</em> behind those workings. This conviction was shared by
      the historical personage whose life is central to <cite>From
      Hell</cite>, although perhaps his beliefs were expressed in a somewhat
      broader sense than my own. For my part, the thing that I am concerned
      with cutting into and examining is the stillwarm corpse of history
      itself. In my chilliest moments, I sometimes suspect that this was
      <em>his</em> foremost preoccupation also, albeit in pursuit of
      different ends.
    </p>
    <author rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Alan_Moore">Alan Moore</author>
    <source>In the Appendix of <cite>From Hell:The Compleat Scripts</cite></source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q96">
    <p>
      This book is dedicated to Polly Nichols, Annie Chapman, Liz Stride,
      Kate Eddowes, and Marie Jeanette Kelly. You and your demise: of these
      things alone are we certain. Goodnight, ladies.
    </p>
    <source>Dedication in the TPB of FROM HELL</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q97">
    <p>
      "The working class don't <em>want</em> a revolution, Mr Lees: they
      just want more money."
    </p>
    <source>Abberline, in the prologue to FROM HELL</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q98">
    <p>
      "Don't you ever feel guilty? We could have said something. We could
      have done something. <em>Why</em>, Fred? Why did we just let them bury
      it?"
    </p>
    <p>
      "Because we didn't want our throats cut. Because we didn't want our
      lights hung over our shoulders."
    </p>
    <source>Lees and Abberline, in the prologue to FROM HELL</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q99">
    <p>
      "Well, if I may not work the ocean I should like to work with
      something of a kind to it... something that flows like the ocean...
      something salt and old."
    </p>
    <source>Gull, as a child, in FROM HELL #2</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q100">
    <p>
      "Though concerning the objects of your pity I fear there's little
      hope."
    </p>
    <p>
      "There <em>must</em> be... even for such unfortunates. Is not all base
      matter gradually ascending; refining itself into pure spirit?"
    </p>
    <p>
      "Assuredly... but some wretches have a downward momentum in their
      lives almost impossible to reverse."
    </p>
    <source>Gull and Hinton, in FROM HELL #2</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q101">
    <p>
      "Consider it: water will of necessity flow downhill, thwarting all our
      best efforts that it should do otherwise. In order that water might
      rise despite itself it must first be transmuted into steam. It must
      first be touched by the purifying spirit of fire."
    </p>
    <source>Gull, in FROM HELL #2</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q102">
    <p>
      "Dorset Street -- the most evil in London, I'm told."
    </p>
    <source>Hinton, in FROM HELL #2</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q103">
    <p>
      "Such minds, Hinton, shaping infinity itself."
    </p>
    <source>Gull, in FROM HELL #2</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q104">
    <p>
      "Fourth dimensional patterns within Eternity's monolith would, he
      suggests, seem merely random events to third-dimensional percipients."
    </p>
    <source>Hinton, in FROM HELL #2</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q105">
    <p>
      "Let us say something peculiar happens in 1788... a century later,
      related events take place. Then again, 50 years later. Then 25 years.
      Then 12. An invisible curve, rising through the centuries."
    </p>
    <source>Hinton, in FROM HELL #2</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q106">
    <p>
      "Can history then be said to have an architecture, Hinton? The notion
      is most glorious and most horrible."
    </p>
    <source>Gull, in FROM HELL #2</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q107">
    <p>
      "Such purpose. I am fifty, my own purpose unrevealed despite
      meaningless laurels."
    </p>
    <source>Gull, in FROM HELL #2</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q108">
    <p>
      "Our son is a wastrel and a halfwit. We shudder to think of the throne
      in his hands. But he is none the less of our flesh and our obligation
      is most severe..."
    </p>
    <source>Queen Victoria, in FROM HELL #2</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q109">
    <p>
      "These times, they are a worry to us, and it has been too long since
      we had men about us who were strong and dependable. Since dear, dear
      Albert... Go. Go now, Dr Gull. We would be alone."
    </p>
    <source>Queen Victoria, in FROM HELL #2</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q110">
    <p>
      "There is a wrong, an intense wrong, in our society running all
      through our life... And it will be made righter some day. I dashed
      myself against it but it is no one man's strength can move it. It was
      too much for my brain, but it is by the failure of some that others
      succeed, and through my very foolishness shall come better success to
      others... perhaps more than any cleverness of mine could have
      wrought."
    </p>
    <source>James Hinton, quoted in FROM HELL #2</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q111">
    <p>
      "Fear not, though thoughts and memories most unendurable beset your
      mind... for I shall take them all away and quite relieve your
      suffering."
    </p>
    <source>Gull, in FROM HELL #2</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q112">
    <p>
      "Less then a thimble-full of iodine divides the intellectual from the
      imbecile. Of which phenomenon I shall forthwith attempt a
      demonstration."
    </p>
    <source>Gull, in FROM HELL #2</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q113">
    <p>
      "I dreamed about Stamford Street, where I lived with my Billy before
      'e ran off..."
    </p>
    <p>
      "Dreams! It's wakin' life's the trouble!"
    </p>
    <source>Polly Nichols and Annie Chapman, in FROM HELL #3</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q114">
    <p>
      "<em>No</em>, sir! Not "Done away with" for that is common murder,
      only fit for common footpads. I spoke of grand work, Netley. Grand
      work. A great work must have many sides from which we may consider
      it."
    </p>
    <source>Gull, in FROM HELL #4</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q115">
    <p>
      "Do you begin to grasp how truly great a work is London? A veritable
      textbook we may draw upon in formulating great works of our own!"
    </p>
    <source>Gull, in FROM HELL #4</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q116">
    <p>
      "The greater part of London's story is not writ in words. It is
      instead a literature of stone, of place-names and assocations."
    </p>
    <source>Gull, in FROM HELL #4</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q117">
    <p>
      "Symbols have <em>power</em>, Netley... Power enough to turn even a
      stomach such as yours, or to deliver half this planet's population
      into slavery."
    </p>
    <source>Gull, in FROM HELL #4</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q118">
    <p>
      "Do whatever needs to be done. You make your cuts, Sir Charles. I'll
      make mine."
    </p>
    <source>Gull, in FROM HELL #5</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q119">
    <p>
      "What a life you have endured, awaiting nothing but deliverance."
    </p>
    <p>
      "Mm. I... Sir? I feel so queer. Does everything look sparkly to you?"
    </p>
    <p>
      "Why, child, that's just the stars. This is a rare and special night,
      I think. For both of us."
    </p>
    <source>Gull and Polly Nichols, in FROM HELL #5</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q120">
    <p>
      "You're forging a letter from a killer? But that's ..."
    </p>
    <p>
      "It's a whole new style of journalism, Mr Gibbs, and we're inventin'
      it right 'ere in Wapping."
    </p>
    <source>Mr Best and Mr Gibbs, in FROM HELL #7</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q121">
    <p>
      "Oh God. I've been tryin' not to think about it. I had such a lovely
      fuck with Joe last night. I thought "Is this it? Is this the last of
      it?"
    </p>
    <source>Mary Kelly, in FROM HELL #8</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q122">
    <p>
      "Gull, please, in the name of reason..."
    </p>
    <p>
      "Invoke not reason. In the end it is too small a deity."
    </p>
    <source>Sir Charles Warren and Gull, in FROM HELL #8</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q123">
    <p>
      "It... ughh... it is these grapes. They have something on them, I
      think."
    </p>
    <p>
      "'tis laudanum. A little, nothing more. They are the grapes of mercy,
      child, not lightly spat away."
    </p>
    <source>Elizabeth Stride and Gull, in FROM HELL #8</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q124">
    <p>
      "If you'll forgive me, Sir, I am Robert Lees, psychic adviser to Her
      Majesty. I am familiar with your work, Sir, and have long anticipated
      this meeting."
    </p>
    <p>
      "Indeed? I am similarly familiar with <em>your</em> work , Sir,
      profiting from delusions born of bereavement. Consequently, I have
      relished this meeting not at all. Good day."
    </p>
    <source>Robert Lees and Gull, in FROM HELL #9</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q125">
    <p>
      "Say what you will, Sir. You are welcome to remain ensconced in lore
      and ritual. For my part I am happy to entertain a questioning spirit."
    </p>
    <p>
      "Ha ha ha! Then mark my words, Mr Yeats, your bones shall never rest
      easy. Good day to you, Sir."
    </p>
    <source>W.B. Yeats and Gull, in FROM HELL #9</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q126">
    <p>
      "Oh, an' I see Anderson's back from 'is Swiss 'olidays, ayin' we
      should arrest every tart for 'er own protection!"
    </p>
    <p>
      "Well, he's one of them Second-Coming Christians, ain't he? Perhaps
      he'll put some of them up at his house."
    </p>
    <source>Abberline and Godley, in FROM HELL #9</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q127">
    <p>
      "There, there, Netley. There, there. I shall tell you where we are.
      We're in the most extreme and utter region of the human mind, a dim
      sub-conscious underworld. A radiant abyss where men meet themselves...
      Hell, Netley. We're in Hell."
    </p>
    <source>Gull, in FROM HELL #9</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q128">
    <p>
      "You're mad."
    </p>
    <p>
      "Oh, undoubtedly. But you're helpless."
    </p>
    <source>Sir Charles Warren and Gull, in FROM HELL #9</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q129">
    <p>
      "Dear God, what is this Aethyr I am come upon? What spirits are these,
      labouring in what heavenly light? No... No, this is dazzle, but not
      yet divinity."
    </p>
    <source>Gull, in FROM HELL #10</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q130">
    <p>
      "It would seem we are to suffer an apocalypse of cockatoos... Morose,
      barbaric children, playing joylessly with their unfathomable toys."
    </p>
    <source>Gull, in FROM HELL #10</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q131">
    <p>
      "Where comes this dullness in your eyes? How has your century numbed
      you so? Shall man be given marvels only when he is beyond all wonder?
    </p>
    <source>Gull, in FROM HELL #10</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q132">
    <p>
      "You are the sum of all preceding you, yet seem indifferent to
      yourselves. A culture grown disinterested, even in its own abysmal
      wounds."
    </p>
    <source>Gull, in FROM HELL #10</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q133">
    <p>
      "Ah, Mary, how time's levelled us. We are made equal, both mere curios
      of our vanished epoch in this lustless world. This world, where in
      comparison I am made ignorant, while you... you are made virtuous."
    </p>
    <source>Gull, in FROM HELL #10</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q134">
    <p>
      "Do you understand how I have loved you? You'd have all been dead in a
      year or two from liver failure, men, or childbirth. Dead. Forgotten. I
      have saved you. Do you understand that? I have made you safe from
      time, and we are wed in legend, inextricable within eternity."
    </p>
    <source>Gull, in FROM HELL #10</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q135">
    <p>
      "Have you done, Sir? Is it finished with?"
    </p>
    <p>
      "It is beginning, Netley. Only just beginning. For better or worse,
      the twentieth century."
    </p>
    <source>Netley and Gull, in FROM HELL #10</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q136">
    <p>
      "I have been climbing, Netley, all my life, toward a single peak. Now
      I have reached it. I have stood and felt the wind. I have seen all the
      world beneath me. Now there is only descent. Only the valley. Would
      that I had died there, Netley, in that light above the cloud line. I'm
      cold. Take me home."
    </p>
    <source>Gull, in FROM HELL #10</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q137">
    <p>
      "I remember my first Fenian bombin', year afore I were first married.
      Makes you think there's naught to us but shit and mincemeat."
    </p>
    <source>Abberline, in FROM HELL #11</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q138">
    <p>
      "To be honest, I felt worse than sick. I came out that room and I felt
      somethin' <em>bad</em> 'ad 'appened. Not just to 'er, to everythin'. I
      felt as if everythin' were lost."
    </p>
    <source>Abberline, in FROM HELL #11</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q139">
    <p>
      "Come on, Godley. Cheer up, for fuck's sake. There's good things
      happen in life as well, y'know."
    </p>
    <p>
      "But... I mean, after that ... that thing in Miller's Court."
    </p>
    <p>
      "I said in <em>life</em>, Godley. I didn't say in the East End."
    </p>
    <source>Abberline and Godley, in FROM HELL #11</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q140">
    <p>
      "Ah, yes. Dear Frank. I'm afraid he's had to retire early with a mild
      touch of insanity."
    </p>
    <source>Oscar Wilde, in FROM HELL #11</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q141">
    <p>
      "Oscar <em>Wilde</em>? Oscar Wilde, the <em>writer</em>?"
    </p>
    <p>
      "Oh, good heavens, no! <em>Awful</em> fellow. Wouldn't give him house-
      room. No, I'm Oscar Wilde the florist. While over <em>here</em> we
      have Mr Walter Sickert, the turf accountant... and Mr James McNeil
      Whistler, who I believe keeps a tripe stall in Mile End."
    </p>
    <source>Montague Druitt and Oscar Wilde, in FROM HELL #11</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q142">
    <p>
      "It's all just stories when all's said and done."
    </p>
    <p>
      "But that's just the thing, it isn't just stories. Those women really
      died. And poor Druitt, caught up in something he could never
      understand."
    </p>
    <p>
      "That's all done with though. That's all gone."
    </p>
    <source>Abberline and Robert Lees, in the epilogue to FROM HELL</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q143">
    <p>
      "Take my advice and don't get old. It's bloody rubbish."
    </p>
    <source>Abberline, in the epilogue to FROM HELL</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q144">
    <p>
      "Now there's just us, knowin' what we know, both washed up 'ere. Can't
      send a message; can't tell anybody. I expect there's been a lot of
      chaps in our position down across the years with one thing and
      another. Makes you wonder, sometimes, doesn't it? Make you wonder 'ow
      much of the world is true."
    </p>
    <source>Abberline, in the epilogue to FROM HELL</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q145">
    <p>
      "I think there's going to be another war."
    </p>
    <source>Robert Lees, in the epilogue to FROM HELL</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q146">
    <p>
      The problem we face here is that neither Knight nor the assembled
      ranks of Freemasonry are necessarily telling the truth, at which point
      a Victorian fog starts to engulf the facts of our narrative. Given
      that the tortuous story of the Whitechapel murders is filled with
      liars, tricksters, and unreliable witnesses, it is a fog we shall
      encounter often.
    </p>
    <author rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Alan_Moore">Alan Moore</author>
    <source>In Appendix I of FROM HELL</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q147">
    <p>
      The character and temperament of Victoria here is entirely my own
      interpretation, and has indeed been the source of debate between
      myself and the otherwise genial and agreeable Mr Campbell of Brisbane,
      Australia.
    </p>
    <author rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Alan_Moore">Alan Moore</author>
    <source>In Appendix I of FROM HELL</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q148">
    <p>
      One almost suspects that the bereaved Victoria, who spent the later
      decades of her reign in mourning for her departed consort, would have
      changed her own name to Albert and the name of the country to Alberta
      if she had thought for a moment she could get away with it.
    </p>
    <author rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Alan_Moore">Alan Moore</author>
    <source>In Appendix I of FROM HELL</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q149">
    <p>
      The phrase, Hairy-Ford-Shire, a rather dim pun upon the pronunciation
      of "Hertfordshire", is one of an extensive array of Victorian slang
      expressions relating to the female genitalia. The expression, in this
      instance, was passed on to me by Mr Neil Gaiman, who has a dirty mouth
      in at least seven centuries.
    </p>
    <author rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Alan_Moore">Alan Moore</author>
    <source>In Appendix I of FROM HELL</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q150">
    <p>
      As with so much of <cite>From Hell</cite>, when we know the details of
      a person's life but not how he or she felt, then we must resort to
      fiction unless we are to exclude feelings altogether, which I don't
      feel inclined to do.
    </p>
    <author rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Alan_Moore">Alan Moore</author>
    <source>In Appendix I of FROM HELL</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q151">
    <p>
      In the case of the fraudulent and press-generated "Ripper" letters, we
      see a clear prototype of the current British tabloid press in action,
      and for this reason it seemed poetically apposite that the letter be
      composed in Wapping, currently the home of Mr Rupert Murdoch's highly
      popular right-wing tabloid, which, unsurprisingly in this tale of
      obelisks and other arcane solar symbols, is called <cite>The
      Sun</cite>.
    </p>
    <author rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Alan_Moore">Alan Moore</author>
    <source>In Appendix I of FROM HELL</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q152">
    <p>
      On the 29th September, the Central News Agency forwarded the letter to
      Scotland Yard that we see Abberline reading aloud here to Thick and
      Godley (and if there were ever two names more emblematic of the police
      force of that period, I should certainly like to hear them).
    </p>
    <author rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Alan_Moore">Alan Moore</author>
    <source>In Appendix I of FROM HELL</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q153">
    <p>
      Abberline's eerily precognitive comments on page two are my own
      invention. They are also, in their way, a form of shamefaced apology
      from one currently making part of his living wrapping up miserable
      little killings in supernatural twaddle. Sometimes, after all you've
      done for them, your characters just turn on you.
    </p>
    <author rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Alan_Moore">Alan Moore</author>
    <source>In Appendix I of FROM HELL</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q154">
    <p>
      Everyone seems agreed that Kelly was the real target. She'd infected
      Dr Stanley's son, corrupted Olga Tchkersoff's sister. The underlying
      assumption remains unstated: she must have done <em>something</em> to
      deserve <em>that</em>.
    </p>
    <author rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Alan_Moore">Alan Moore</author>
    <source>In "Dance of the Gull-Catchers" in FROM HELL</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q155">
    <p>
      By Autumn 1988 I'm thinking of seriously about writing something
      lengthy on a murder. The Whitechapel killings aren't even considered.
      Too played-out. Too obvious. Publicity around the crimes' centennial,
      however, leads me to Knight's book. Ideas coalesce. Deciding on a
      serial in Steve Bissette's <cite>Taboo</cite>, I contact Eddie
      Campbell. The rest is dodgy pseudo-history.
    </p>
    <author rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Alan_Moore">Alan Moore</author>
    <source>In "Dance of the Gull-Catchers" in FROM HELL</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q156">
    <p>
      Be vewy, vewy quiet. We're hunting Wippers.
    </p>
    <author rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Alan_Moore">Alan Moore</author>
    <source>In "Dance of the Gull-Catchers" in FROM HELL</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q157">
    <p>
      Slowly it dawns on me that despite the Gull theory's obvious
      attractions, the idea of a solution, any solution, is inane. Murder
      isn't like books. Murder, a human event located in both space and
      time, has an imaginary field completely unrestrained by either. It
      holds meaning, and shape, but no solution.
    </p>
    <author rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Alan_Moore">Alan Moore</author>
    <source>In "Dance of the Gull-Catchers" in FROM HELL</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q158">
    <p>
      The grounds of the enquiry are a forensic sucking-bog; treacherous,
      obsessional. Fall in this stuff and you won't come out again.
    </p>
    <author rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Alan_Moore">Alan Moore</author>
    <source>In "Dance of the Gull-Catchers" in FROM HELL</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q159">
    <p>
      Reputedly, many prominent Ripperologists never set foot in Whitechapel
      for fear of being mugged. Mugging's not the danger here. This place is
      authentically dreadful.
    </p>
    <author rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Alan_Moore">Alan Moore</author>
    <source>In "Dance of the Gull-Catchers" in FROM HELL</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q160">
    <p>
      It isn't getting drawn into Masonic Death Conspiracy that troubles me,
      you understand. It's getting drawn into the vortex of a fiction.
    </p>
    <author rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Alan_Moore">Alan Moore</author>
    <source>In "Dance of the Gull-Catchers" in FROM HELL</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q161">
    <p>
      Some stories just don't have what it takes. The yarn that eventually
      survives to be accepted as history will do so by brute Darwinian
      mechanics. We'll lock all the suspects in a room together. They can
      fight it out.
    </p>
    <author rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Alan_Moore">Alan Moore</author>
    <source>In "Dance of the Gull-Catchers" in FROM HELL</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q162">
    <p>
      Our detective fictions tell us otherwise: everything's just meat and
      cold ballistics. Provide a murderer, a motive, and a means, you've
      solved the crime. Using this method, the solution to the Second World
      War is as follows: Hitler. The German economy. Tanks. Thus, for
      convenience, we reduce the complex events.
    </p>
    <author rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Alan_Moore">Alan Moore</author>
    <source>In "Dance of the Gull-Catchers" in FROM HELL</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q163">
    <p>
      The greater part of any murder is the field of theory, fascination and
      hysteria that it engenders. A black diaspora. Our tireless, sinister
      enthusiasm.
    </p>
    <author rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Alan_Moore">Alan Moore</author>
    <source>In "Dance of the Gull-Catchers" in FROM HELL</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q164">
    <p>
      Soon, somebody will notice the disturbing similarities between the
      Ripper crimes and recent cattle mutilations, from which they will draw
      the only sensible conclusion.
    </p>
    <author rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Alan_Moore">Alan Moore</author>
    <source>In "Dance of the Gull-Catchers" in FROM HELL</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q165">
    <p>
      Likewise, each new book provides fresh details, finer crennelations of
      the subject's edge. Its area, however, can't extend past the initial
      circle: Autumn, 1888, Whitechapel. ... Koch's Snowflake: gaze upon it,
      Ripperologists, and shiver.
    </p>
    <author rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Alan_Moore">Alan Moore</author>
    <source>In "Dance of the Gull-Catchers" in FROM HELL</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q166">
    <p>
      The complex phantom we project. That alone, we know is real. The
      actual killer's gone, unglimpsed. Might as well not have been there at
      all. There never was a Jack the Ripper. Mary Kelly was just an
      unusually determined suicide. Why don't we leave it there?
    </p>
    <author rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Alan_Moore">Alan Moore</author>
    <source>In "Dance of the Gull-Catchers" in FROM HELL</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q167">
    <p>
      It's going. It's all going. Will anybody bother with a bicentennial in
      2088? Might our pursuit, our quarry, already endangered, be by then
      extinct?
    </p>
    <p>
      We were looking at the naked woman dancing when it flew away.
    </p>
    <author rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Alan_Moore">Alan Moore</author>
    <source>In "Dance of the Gull-Catchers" in FROM HELL</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q168">
    <p>
      Childbirth is <em>not</em> a miracle. Life is <em>not</em> sacred.
      When you have twenty thousand nomads huddled between two rivers in the
      Middle East and that's it for Homo sapiens, when one in five children
      is a live birth, one in ten living past the age of ten, <em>then</em>
      childbirth <em>is</em> a miracle and life <em>is</em> sacred. When the
      average age of a grandmother in Philadelphia's housing projects is
      twenty-five, to call childbirth a miracle is at least a tasteless joke
      and at worst a true obscenity.
    </p>
    <author rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Dave_Sim">Dave Sim</author>
    <source>In the lettercol of Cerebus #142</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q169">
    <p>
      <em>Do not wander off without me.</em> That's how we lost Amelia
      Earhart in here. Every day, about two in the afternoon, the thermals
      are right, and we hear her somewhere in here, screaming for peanut
      buttter and jelly sandwiches.
    </p>
    <source>Harlan's our genial guide through HARLAN ELLISON'S DREAM CORRIDOR Special.</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q170">
    <p>
      You'd have liked my father. He was a sweet guy. He died when I was
      fourteen, but when I was a little kid we used to sit together and I'd
      read my comic books to him. I don't think he cared much about the
      silly stuff in comics -- that was the '40s -- but he loved me and took
      pleasure in my reading aloud to him. I miss my dad.
    </p>
    <source>Harlan remembers his childhood, in HARLAN ELLISON'S DREAM CORRIDOR #2</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q171">
    <p>
      But, if you have a moment, if your heart is big enough to spare a
      moment, give a nod and a smile for all the good ones who spent their
      lives making great art and small art and even entertainment. When
      they're gone, there's only one way to tell them you miss them... Send
      them a moment of kind thought right now. The beam will pick it up and
      carry it across the stars to them where they wait. I've been sending
      good wishes to the ones I miss all evening. Now it's your turn.
    </p>
    <source>Harlan's soliloquy in HARLAN ELLISON'S DREAM CORRIDOR #5</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q172">
    <p>
      When I say that Seth will have his testicles torn off, I do not mean
      that his sac will always be a ragged void. If the gods are not exactly
      a law unto themselves, they can at least bend the rules. In other
      words, some balls bounce back.
    </p>
    <source>Peter Milligan's opening sentences in EGYPT #1</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q173">
    <p>
      I had it in me to be the Pierce Brosnan of my generation.
    </p>
    <source>Vincent Me's past career plans in EGYPT #1</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q174">
    <p>
      Vincent, you are a damaged person who uses sexual gratification as a
      displacement activity. Now get your hand off my behind.
    </p>
    <source>Ooh, good putdown! in EGYPT #1</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q175">
    <p>
      I simply reject the capitalist credo. I reject anything that ends in
      'ist' or 'ism'. In fact, I reject anything that ends in 's'.
    </p>
    <source>Is Vincent for real? In EGYPT #1</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q176">
    <p>
      Years later I was regaining consciousness in America, which is no mean
      feat.
    </p>
    <source>Waking from memories of a sister, in EGYPT #1</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q177">
    <p>
      "The Order of Osiris, the Order of the Listless One, oh God of
      Yesterday, He-Who-Is-Awakened, Lord of the Chennet, the suffering god
      from whose inert body..."
    </p>
    <p>
      "I've got Latin in four hours, Josh. Let's get on with it."
    </p>
    <p>
      "Oh, sorry, of course. Got a little carried away..."
    </p>
    <source>My college years weren't like this! In EGYPT #1</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q178">
    <p>
      "We got to thinking: how did the priests know exactly how long to
      suffocate the new pharaoh for?"
    </p>
    <p>
      "Ah, ah, preposition at the end of a sentence, Kim. You owe me a
      dollar."
    </p>
    <source>Kim and Bobby in EGYPT #1</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q179">
    <p>
      Three hundred years of tears have soured the very stones of this
      house. Drink deep, gentle reader: you have come too far to turn back
      now.
    </p>
    <source>Bethlehem Hospital, or Bedlam, in SEBASTIAN O #1</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q180">
    <p>
      But we cannot disguise our abhorrence of modern communication devices.
    </p>
    <source>Queen Victoria on teleconferencing, in SEBASTIAN O #1</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q181">
    <p>
      The dandy has one unique advantage over the common herd. No matter
      what the situation, he will always be more exquisitely dressed than
      his enemies. Therefore, he has already triumphed.
    </p>
    <source>Sebastian, in SEBASTIAN O #1</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q182">
    <p>
      One must commit acts of the highest treason only when dressed in the
      most resplendent finery.
    </p>
    <source>Sebastian, in SEBASTIAN O #1</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q183">
    <p>
      We may be in the sewer, but there's absolutely no need for that kind
      of gutter profanity.
    </p>
    <source>Sebastian, in SEBASTIAN O #2</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q184">
    <p>
      If I know Sebastian, he'll find it impossible to continue his mission
      in soiled clothing.
    </p>
    <source>Lord Lavender, in SEBASTIAN O #2</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q185">
    <p>
      And now let us hasten to the station. I have commanded the rain to
      fall at exactly one-fifteen and I would hate to get my shoes wet.
    </p>
    <source>Lord Lavender, in SEBASTIAN O #2</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q186">
    <p>
      I do so loathe nature, don't you? All that dreadful rot and decay and
      procreation. Here, everything is so much more tidy. I simply wind the
      trees once a day and reset the flowers.
    </p>
    <source>The Abb does love his clockwork garden, in SEBASTIAN O #2</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q187">
    <p>
      It would take days to catalog your sins, Abb. I simply don't have the
      time.
    </p>
    <source>Sebastian, in SEBASTIAN O #2</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q188">
    <p>
      The Abb, I'm afraid, has gone to meet his maker. Hard to decide which
      of the two will receive the greater shock.
    </p>
    <source>Sebastian, in SEBASTIAN O #3</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q189">
    <p>
      "Don't fret, Theo. The lad's simply stunned. He'll wake up in an hour,
      none the wiser."
    </p>
    <p>
      "But his throat has been cut."
    </p>
    <p>
      "Oh, dear, my mistake. My diagnosis regarding his recovery would
      appear to have been somewhat premature."
    </p>
    <source>Sebastian and Lord Lavender, in SEBASTIAN O #3</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q190">
    <p>
      First... a pardon. I should hate to be hounded further for acts which
      some might consider crimes, but which I prefer to think of as
      aesthetic statements. I have, after all, killed only the <em>very</em>
      dull.
    </p>
    <source>Sebastian, in SEBASTIAN O #3</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q191">
    <p>
      One hardly requires the abilities of a Tiresias to predict fog in
      London. What other revelations have you to offer, Theo? That the Grand
      National will be won by a <em>horse</em> this year, perhaps?
    </p>
    <source>Sebastian, in SEBASTIAN O #3</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q192">
    <p>
      We're beginning to think it may be a neurological disorder, similar to
      Tourette's Syndrome. It's quite possible we may be looking at some
      kind of super-sanity here. A brilliant new modification of human
      perception, more suited to urban life at the end of the twentieth
      century.
    </p>
    <source>Ruth Adams describes the Joker in ARKHAM ASYLUM</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q193">
    <p>
      You must be feeling quite <em>fragile</em> by now, I expect. This
      house, it... <em>does</em> things to the mind.
    </p>
    <source>The Mad Hatter in ARKHAM ASYLUM</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q194">
    <p>
      I pity the poor shades confined to the Euclidean prison that is
      sanity.
    </p>
    <source>From Amadeus Arkham's journal in ARKHAM ASYLUM</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q195">
    <p>
      I should say I'm very much cleverer than any of the people who put me
      here. As a matter of fact, I could leave any time I wanted. It's only
      a doll's house after all. Anyway, I don't mind. I like dolls.
      Particularly the live ones.
    </p>
    <source>Mad Hatter's thoughts in ARKHAM ASYLUM</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q196">
    <p>
      "And if you want something hotter, you know where to find me."
    </p>
    <p>
      "In the gutter on a Friday night, Tony."
    </p>
    <source>Tony and Annie in THE MYSTERY PLAY</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q197">
    <p>
      Not every day one has God on the slab, eh?
    </p>
    <source>The coroner in THE MYSTERY PLAY</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q198">
    <p>
      "God is in the details," after all. Or in this case, perhaps, the
      details are in God.
    </p>
    <source>The coroner in THE MYSTERY PLAY</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q199">
    <p>
      I think everything that happens in the vicinity of a murder has some
      significance: the flight of birds, the shape of the clouds, the
      positions of the stars, items discarded by passersby. Nothing can be
      overlooked. If I find a match, I have to know where it was made and
      from what tree its wood was taken.
    </p>
    <source>The detective in THE MYSTERY PLAY</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q200">
    <p>
      I'm not a metaphysical man. I'm a minister. That's my job.
    </p>
    <source>The minister in THE MYSTERY PLAY</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q201">
    <p>
      I was somebody else once. I... I... don't think I was a very good
      person.
    </p>
    <source>The detective in THE MYSTERY PLAY</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q202">
    <p>
      "The killer's still out there, Mr Purves. I hope Christ has taken out
      life insurance."
    </p>
    <p>
      "Oh, I'm sure any firm would jump at the chance to ensure a man who
      has eternal life, don't you?"
    </p>
    <source>The detective and the mayor in THE MYSTERY PLAY</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q203">
    <p>
      Well, me whole family's musical, Jeffo... even the sewing machine's a
      Singer.
    </p>
    <source>John Constantine in HELLBLAZER #90</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q204">
    <p>
      It's a little-known legend is Abaton -- the town of changing
      locations. Philosophers, mystics and clever-bastards-in-general have
      known of its existence for centuries.
    </p>
    <source>In HELLBLAZER #93</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q205">
    <p>
      As I follow the green man up the narrow path, visions of electric
      hedge trimmers go swimming through my brain.
    </p>
    <source>John Constantine in HELLBLAZER #93</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q206">
    <p>
      You are in a beautifully wooded area covered with flowers, blah-blah-
      blah...
    </p>
    <source>John Constantine in HELLBLAZER #93</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q207">
    <p>
      If Abaton's the unearthly reflection of all that we are, Britain's in
      far worse shape than I thought.
    </p>
    <source>John Constantine in HELLBLAZER #93</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q208">
    <p>
      I've always believed that guilt was an emotion for weaker men -- so
      where does that leave me?
    </p>
    <source>Wesley Dodds, in SANDMAN MYSTERY THEATRE: "The Cannon", act I</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q209">
    <p>
      Ah, love... so much better than the alternative.
    </p>
    <source>Rev. Hawsley, in SANDMAN MYSTERY THEATRE: "The Cannon", act I</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q210">
    <p>
      He's clouds or fires now.
    </p>
    <source>The Cannon finds Donald Eversoll's body, in SANDMAN MYSTERY THEATRE: "The Cannon", act II</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q211">
    <p>
      Good news is he don't have to go to work tomorrow. Bad news is the
      same.
    </p>
    <source>Lt. Burke finds Donald Eversoll's body, in SANDMAN MYSTERY THEATRE: "The Cannon", act II</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q212">
    <p>
      "I'm surprised you don't think justice is best left to higher powers,
      Bagsy?"
    </p>
    <p>
      "I do, Dian -- I just want to make sure He knows where to look."
    </p>
    <source>Dian and Rev. Hawsley, in SANDMAN MYSTERY THEATRE: "The Cannon", act IV</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q213">
    <p>
      "And are your Lord's lessons learned in <em>you</em>, Cannon?"
    </p>
    <p>
      "I am confident that I will pass through St. Peter's gates with only
      minor negotiations."
    </p>
    <source>The Sandman and the Cannon, in SANDMAN MYSTERY THEATRE: "The Cannon", act IV</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q214">
    <p>
      Good job, there, O'Grady. Always kick 'em when they're down. You might
      just make a detective yet.
    </p>
    <source>Lt. Burke, in SANDMAN MYSTERY THEATRE: "The Cannon", act IV</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q215">
    <p>
      There are very few people who directly touch my daily life -- and I
      can't imagine how much poorer I'd be without any of them.
    </p>
    <source>Wesley Dodds, in SANDMAN MYSTERY THEATRE: "The City", act I</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation><p>
    I was happy in that field. I could have stayed there forever.
    I liked life in those days.  I thought life was my best friend.
    </p><p>
    I was a happy little idiot, really.
    </p><source>Kathy, in SHADE #1: "Execution Day"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation><p>
    I read a pamphlet on alcohol abuse once.  It said alcohol turns
    you into a different person.  I thought, "Great!  That's for me!"
    But it was no good.  You always wake up or sober up the same
    person.  With a headache.
    </p><source>Kathy, in SHADE #1: "Execution Day"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation><p>
    Shade said all the madness inside people's heads will be released,
    made real.  The sky looks really weird today.  The colors look
    wrong.  The clouds look wrong.  Everything looks wrong.  Welcome
    to the madhouse.
    </p><source>Kathy, in SHADE #1: "Execution Day"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation><p>
    "I'm your liberated dreams, baby.  Your liberated dreams and your
    unfettered screams..."
   </p><p>
   "No!  I don't want my dreams to be liberated.  Our dreams are too
   terrible to be liberated!"
    </p>
    <source>The American Scream and Duane, in SHADE #2: "Who Shot JFK?"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation><p>
    His teeth will always be perfect, his smile the smile of a sun
    god, his wife beside him and perfect.  Texan sun on the limo's
    perfect polished bonnet...
    </p><source>From SHADE #2: "Who Shot JFK?"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation><p>
    And out it comes, out it grows.  From the womb of Dallas,
    impregnated by seeds of blood and brain and bone, of conspiracy
    and deceit, of cowardice and corruption and greed, planted here on
    a hot bad Friday.  Fifteen seconds past 12:30 PM, November 22,
    1963...
    </p><p>
    The Kennedy sphinx... And who shall answer his riddle?
    </p><source>From SHADE #2: "Who Shot JFK?"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation><p>
    So the person chosen to be the leader of your country was
    murdered, and you had something called the Warren Commission to
    cover it all up.  And the people really responsible were never
    even named.  And the people you employ to protect you, the CIA,
    the FBI, they actually helped the people responsible to get away
    with it?  And this was a popular president?  What happens with an
    unpopular president?  Do you just leave him in the gutter to rot
    or what?
    </p><source>Shade, in SHADE #2: "Who Shot JFK?"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation><p>This sphinx doesn't strangle.  This sphinx is the
  Kennedy sphinx.  This sphinx is American.  It consumes.  It eats.
    </p><source>From SHADE #2: "Who Shot JFK?"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation><p>
    Cancer is rather interesting.  I believe it's a kind of wearing
    out of information.  Runaway cells who've forgotten who they are
    or where they're going.  But it mightn't be restricted to
    creatures or cells.  Why not cancer of civilization?  Why not
    cancer of the imagination?  Imagine a cancer of reality.
    </p><source>Stringer, in SHADE #2: "Who Shot JFK?"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation><p>"Bobby?  Jesus... And what about Teddy?  They get Teddy, too?"
    </p><p>
    "Ahhh, no.  They didn't need to wipe Teddy out.  Teddy was doing a
    fine job of that himself."
    </p><source>JFK and Duane, in SHADE #3: "All the President's Assassins"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation><p>I must be plastic.  I must transpose myself into a new
   and mad view of reality.
    </p><source>Shade, in SHADE #3: "All the President's Assassins"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation><p>The past is a branch, forking through and out from
  Dallas.  There's more than one truth, more than one assassin.  But
  behind them all is the same hand, the shadow of the same
  creature... let's go deeper still...
    </p><source>Mary Ann, in SHADE #3: "All the President's Assassins"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation><p>Oh, the Mob and the CIA are just the high priests, the
  guardians of America's divinity... which is usually green and comes
  with a picture of Mr. Washington on one side and the words "In God
  We Trust" on the other...
    </p><source>Mary Ann, in SHADE #3: "All the President's Assassins"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation><p>"I say we fly in the choppers, drop a few dozen
  grenades and swamp the whole area with napalm.   See how the big
  bastard copes with that..."
    </p><p>
    "You sentimental old liberal, Hopgood.  Don't you think we should
    try the direct approach?"
    </p><source>Hopgood and Stringer, in SHADE #3: "All the President's Assassins"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation><p>You know, I've a horrible feeling that if we get much
  deeper into this madness we're gonna end up having a religious
  experience.  And I vowed long ago never to have one of those.
    </p><source>Kathy, in SHADE #3: "All the President's Assassins"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation><p>And I am the American Scream, <foreign>e pluribus
  unum</foreign>,  out of many, one...  Giver of voice and flesh to
  the quiet screams of unquiet minds.
    </p><source>The Scream, in SHADE #4: "Mad, Bad, and Dangerous to Know"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation><p>I used to stare at flowers, rage at death, cry at
  sunsets.  After my confirmation, I was too sensible for that.  I
  enrolled at college, took my occupational personality test, cried at
  no more sunsets.   I was a dull little bastard, like all the others.
    </p><source>Shade, in SHADE #4: "Mad, Bad, and Dangerous to Know"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation><p>And I smile, as a man might smile looking round the
  ruins of his house, and finding something he thought he'd lost long,
  long ago.
    </p><source>Shade, in SHADE #4: "Mad, Bad, and Dangerous to Know"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation><p>How I enjoy people who refer to themselves in the
  third person!  It's as though they were reciting from their own
  biography.
  And a biography of a person is always so much more interesting than
  the person himself.
    </p><source>Crispin Keen, in SHADE #5: "Hollywood Babble On"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation><p>"Yeah, I heard she'd screw a horse if it meant acting
  with Brando."
  </p><p>
  "If it'd help her career she'd screw Brando if it meant acting with
  a horse."
    </p><source>Edward and William, in SHADE #5: "Hollywood Babble On"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation><p>"What do you do in America once the money's run out."
    </p><p>"Starve."
    </p><source>Shade and Kathy, in SHADE #5: "Hollywood Babble On"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation><p>You can't escape it.  Everywhere there are screens,
  pictures, images, sounds.  They won't let you be alone.  America is
  scared of being alone.
    </p><source>From SHADE #5: "Hollywood Babble On"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q216">
    <p>
      "But a camera's just a machine. It can't have the madness. That
      doesn't make sense."
    </p>
    <p>
      "If it made sense it wouldn't be the madness, would it?"
    </p>
    <source>Kathy and Shade, in SHADE #6: "Hollywood Babble On II"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q217">
    <p>
      I <em>must</em> keep a clear head. If I'm to survive with my mind
      intact, I must put my queer shoulder firmly to the wheel of
      objectivity.
    </p>
    <source>Crispen Keen, in SHADE #6: "Hollywood Babble On II"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q218">
    <p>
      All the years the public lived vicariously through film, now they're
      living it. But life isn't like film. Life's got too many plot defects.
      Whom to blame? Who's the director, the <foreign>auteur</foreign> of
      life? Who writes these utterly absurd screenplays? God? But God
      doesn't exist. And if he does he's more Godard than Spielberg.
    </p>
    <source>Crispen Keen, in SHADE #6: "Hollywood Babble On II"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q219">
    <p>
      Guess this changes things, though. If inanimate objects can get the
      madness... an insane coffee cup. A schizophrenic shirt...
    </p>
    <source>Shade, in SHADE #6: "Hollywood Babble On II"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q220">
    <p>
      "Nice tits, by the way."
    </p>
    <p>
      "Jesus, we got a date with Oscar Wilde..."
    </p>
    <source>Shade and a post-modern prostitute, in SHADE #64</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q221">
    <p>
      "I think she looks the type that will see through the whole charade."
    </p>
    <p>
      "Yeah. We're just visible signs of his inner trepidation coupled with
      a fear of commitment..."
    </p>
    <p>
      "Excuse me! I said, excuse me! Prostitutes! Ladies of the night!
      Streetwalkers! I'm talking to you!"
    </p>
    <source>Two post-modern prostitutes and Shade, in SHADE #64</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q222">
    <p>
      So that's two bottles of bourbon, twenty beers and four clubs to room
      one oh one... and if it isn't here in fifteen minutes we'll set fire
      to the hotel.
    </p>
    <source>Andrea Merdoch ordering from room service in SHADE #64</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q223">
    <p>
      "You mean you want to help the people who've been hurt?"
    </p>
    <p>
      "Actually, I was thinking more about me and my quality of life. But if
      people get helped as a byproduct I can live with it."
    </p>
    <source>Sinita and Shade in SHADE #64</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q224">
    <p>
      Hell... the most awful place you can imagine. Currently under new
      management, now guaranteed to be even worse.
    </p>
    <source>STANLEY AND HIS MONSTER #1</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q225">
    <p>
      "Zzzxxynax (Spit/Drool) Bite-your-dog's-head-off Zznoq?"
    </p>
    <p>
      "Here."
    </p>
    <source>Remiel calling attendance in Hell, in STANLEY AND HIS MONSTER #1</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q226">
    <p>
      Earth... the most awful place you can imagine, if you live in Los
      Angeles. Other than that, it's pretty neat.
    </p>
    <source>STANLEY AND HIS MONSTER #1</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q227">
    <p>
      "Hey, here's some more stuff from the Bicentennial! (ahem) 'My
      friends, taxes are too high and the government treats us like idiots,
      so I'm revolting.'"
    </p>
    <p>
      "At least you had an excuse."
    </p>
    <source>Stanley and his monster, in STANLEY AND HIS MONSTER #1</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q228">
    <p>
      "Look, here's a book."
    </p>
    <p>
      "Not another copy of <cite>Jonathan Livingston Seagull</cite>, is it?"
    </p>
    <source>Stanley and his monster, in STANLEY AND HIS MONSTER #1</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q229">
    <p>
      Yum, genuine polyester!
    </p>
    <source>The monster, in STANLEY AND HIS MONSTER #1</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q230">
    <p>
      Better get going; your parents still think me imaginary, and I'd hate
      to shatter an illusion like that before dinner.
    </p>
    <source>The monster, in STANLEY AND HIS MONSTER #1</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q231">
    <p>
      "Take this book back to my room, and <em>don't eat it</em>!"
    </p>
    <p>
      "Stanley, you wound me. I already have this delicious stack of
      <cite>National Geographics</cite>, thank you."
    </p>
    <source>Stanley and his monster, in STANLEY AND HIS MONSTER #1</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q232">
    <p>
      "Great! Tomorrow we find the right tree!"
    </p>
    <p>
      "What're our criteria?"
    </p>
    <p>
      "One you won't break."
    </p>
    <source>Stanley and his monster, in STANLEY AND HIS MONSTER #1</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q233">
    <p>
      "Hell sounds like a very silly place. Don't you miss it?"
    </p>
    <p>
      "No. Not even a little, Stanley. You see, we'd... play tricks on each
      other all the time... but nobody was your friend. Not really. Nobody
      was <em>anybody's</em> friend."
    </p>
    <source>The monster reminiscing, in STANLEY AND HIS MONSTER #1</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q234">
    <p>
      That is <em>quite</em> enough. I mean really, Stanley, I'm afraid
      you've exceeded your special effects budget for this entire month. Not
      to mention the casting calls I've had to sit through. I'm afraid that
      you'll be dreaming about the ocean for the next several weeks. I
      happen to have a lot of it in stock. Perhaps it will calm you down.
      Good night.
    </p>
    <source>Morpheus, Lord of Dreams, makes a nicely characterized guest appearance in STANLEY AND HIS MONSTER #1</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q235">
    <p>
      "So what's so bad about her?"
    </p>
    <p>
      "To answer that, Stanley, I'd have to tell you about the birds and the
      bees... and the chainsaws, and the weasels, and the icepicks, and the
      acid, and the..."
    </p>
    <source>The monster's introduction to his lady-love Nyx, on the cover of STANLEY AND HIS MONSTER #2</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q236">
    <p>
      "Aha! I knew I'd find you here!"
    </p>
    <p>
      "Huh? Well, good for you. Now it's your turn to hide."
    </p>
    <source>Weevil Dendrite and Ambrose Bierce in STANLEY AND HIS MONSTER #2</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q237">
    <p>
      "'Disreputable Urban Magicians and Sorcerors Union' Oh...sorry."
    </p>
    <p>
      "Ah, s'not your fault. You learn the basics, have a hideous experience
      in a graveyard, they give you a trenchcoat and steal your razor. Like
      an assembly line, really."
    </p>
    <source>Weevil Dendrite and Ambrose Bierce in STANLEY AND HIS MONSTER #2</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q238">
    <p>
      I've created my own form of divination. One that allows me to capture
      the currents of chaos in mid-motion and study the fluxes themselves. I
      call it-- JELLOMANCY!
    </p>
    <source>Weevil Dendrite explains his magic, in STANLEY AND HIS MONSTER #2</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q239">
    <p>
      "And you're a rhymer now. How... nice."
    </p>
    <p>
      "Like it? Actually I'm still just apprenticing. They've been starting
      me off slow. Enchantments, prophecies of doom, greeting cards, stuff
      like that."
    </p>
    <source>The monster and Nyx, in STANLEY AND HIS MONSTER #2</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q240">
    <p>
      You'll die gloriously, I promise you. Well, actually, you're going to
      die slowly and painfully, but it's nothing a little editing won't fix.
    </p>
    <source>A battle-enraged Nyx, in STANLEY AND HIS MONSTER #2</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q241">
    <p>
      Luckily, every good story is allowed one astounding coincidence. The
      writer has decided to cash his in now.
    </p>
    <source>In Phil Foglio's STANLEY AND HIS MONSTER #2</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q242">
    <p>
      That does it! I cannot understand why everybody speaks so well of
      'subtlety.' It never works, I don't know why I even try anymore!!
      Now!! Tell me, mortal scum, where is he?!
    </p>
    <source>Nyx throws in the towel, in STANLEY AND HIS MONSTER #2</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q243">
    <p>
      "Yes, that hideous thing that looked like my wife!"
    </p>
    <p>
      "<em>I beg your pardon?!</em>"
    </p>
    <p>
      "But Sheila, I didn't... I mean, she really was lovely--"
    </p>
    <p>
      "<em>Is</em> <em>that</em> <em>so</em>?"
    </p>
    <p>
      "But it was a hideous evil sort of lovely!"
    </p>
    <source>Wedded bliss, in STANLEY AND HIS MONSTER #3</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q244">
    <p>
      "But what did they call you?"
    </p>
    <p>
      "'Big-shaggy-red-spirit-dog-who-protects-village.' It's not like there
      were a lot of us around."
    </p>
    <source>Stanley's mother and the monster in STANLEY AND HIS MONSTER #3</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q245">
    <p>
      "I don't think you can fit under the bed."
    </p>
    <p>
      "Oh, there are some ladies who'd tell you otherwise."
    </p>
    <source>Stanley and Ambrose Bierce in STANLEY AND HIS MONSTER #3</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q246">
    <p>
      "Do you happen to know that consciousness is the creature of rhythm?"
    </p>
    <p>
      "No, but if you hum a few bars..."
    </p>
    <p>
      "Humf. You are not him."
    </p>
    <p>
      "(Boy, and I thought the the Church of the Sub-Genius was weird.)"
    </p>
    <source>Stanley's father and a servant of Moxon in STANLEY AND HIS MONSTER #3</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q247">
    <p>
      "Okay, we've got all the ingredients for 'spaghetti'. You know, I
      think this would be pretty good if you threw in some turpentine and a
      few centipedes."
    </p>
    <p>
      "I think the first time out we should just stick to the recipe."
    </p>
    <source>The monster and Stanley in STANLEY AND HIS MONSTER #3</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q248">
    <p>
      "Where are we, Mr Bierce?"
    </p>
    <p>
      "There are many realms between the spheres of life and death, Stanley.
      No magician can explore them all."
    </p>
    <p>
      "You don't know."
    </p>
    <source>Ambrose Bierce and Stanley in STANLEY AND HIS MONSTER #4</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q249">
    <p>
      "I'll be curious to see what he thinks Hell is."
    </p>
    <p>
      "Garn, I hope he ain't British. Some of that stuff them people dream
      up... it's enough to gag a maggot."
    </p>
    <source>Demons awaiting Stanley's arrival in Hell in STANLEY AND HIS MONSTER #4</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q250">
    <p>
      What kind of theological education are kids getting today?!
    </p>
    <source>An highly-annoyed goofy-looking orange demon in STANLEY AND HIS MONSTER #4</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q251">
    <p>
      Bar-B-Q sauce? Damnit, Nyx, what do you think that will do, you
      ignorant-- Uh-oh. Oh no! Cerberus? Buddy? Good dog?
    </p>
    <source>Glyfford gets a sinking feeling in STANLEY AND HIS MONSTER #4</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q252">
    <p>
      I'm here for the FBI, not the <cite>Weekly World News</cite>.
    </p>
    <source>Scully in X-FILES #1</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q253">
    <p>
      "That isn't the real Shroud of Turin, is it?"
    </p>
    <p>
      "No, Agent Mulder. Just a replica. I keep the original in the
      basement, next to the Holy Grail."
    </p>
    <source>Mulder and Mr. Newton in X-FILES #1</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q254">
    <p>
      "You're off the case! Go chase Bigfoot!
    </p>
    <p>
      "I'd love to, Sir, but with all due respect, the season is wrong.
      Bigfoot sightings taper off in the winter. Unless you were suggesting
      I go to China, where reports of a beast-man are..."
    </p>
    <source>The Smoking Man and Mulder in X-FILES #1</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q255">
    <p>
      Mulder! We are not alone!
    </p>
    <source>Scully in X-FILES #1</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q256">
    <p>
      "Everyone else got to read the Fatima prophecy... and all I got was
      this lousy T-shirt." Thanks. I'll treasure it always.
    </p>
    <source>Mulder gets a Christmas gift from Scully in X-FILES #1</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q257">
    <p>
      It would be such a relief to think my sister's happy, but when I look
      up at the heavens, all I see are the stars.
    </p>
    <source>Mulder in X-FILES #1</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q258">
    <p>
      "Hey, Mulder... how was therapy?"
    </p>
    <p>
      "Pretty good. Today I remembered getting my first library card.
      Unfortunately, the name on it was Hans Holzer."
    </p>
    <source>Scully and Mulder reassemble their memories in X-FILES #2</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q259">
    <p>
      "Ah, you remember our names, Mulder. Recovering?"
    </p>
    <p>
      "Still some gaps, Byers. The phrase 'Rosebud' rings a bell, but I
      can't place it."
    </p>
    <source>Mulder and Byers, in X-FILES #3</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q260">
    <p>
      "You know, when we heard you'd debunked Neola, we were afraid you'd
      gone over to the other side."
    </p>
    <p>
      "Nah -- the hours stink but the pay's good."
    </p>
    <source>Frohike and Mulder, in X-FILES #3</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q261">
    <p>
      "Congratulations. You're finally meeting one of those magical
      creatures you've spent so much time looking for. "
    </p>
    <p>
      "Funny... you don't look like a leprechaun, Lieutenant Colonel Dunne."
    </p>
    <source>Dunne and Mulder in X-FILES #3</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q262">
    <p>
      "Mulder... this disk wouldn't contain Pentagon access codes, would
      it?"
    </p>
    <p>
      "Actually it's Doom II. You know how the Bureau frowns on computer
      games."
    </p>
    <source>Scully and Mulder in X-FILES #3</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q263">
    <p>
      Now that you're dead, Mulder and Scully and Drake, as dead as the
      trees in December, maybe you can understand what it is that I am.
    </p>
    <source>The narrator, in X-FILES #7</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q264">
    <p>
      Our friend believes that, unlike us working stiffs, he lives backwards
      and forwards in time.
    </p>
    <source>Mulder, in X-FILES #7</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q265">
    <p>
      And all the while, the computers dreamed of zeroes and ones -- unable
      to imagine a two.
    </p>
    <source>The narrator, in X-FILES #7</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q266">
    <p>
      "Who are you?"
    </p>
    <p>
      "Oh, pardon me ... Zachary T. Paleozogt, at your service. But you can
      call me Zot!"
    </p>
    <source>Jenny and Zot, in ZOT! #1</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q267">
    <p>
      Welcome, one and all, to the far-flung future of -- 1965!
    </p>
    <source>Zot, in ZOT! #1</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q268">
    <p>
      "Aww, c'mon! Where's your sense of fun?"
    </p>
    <p>
      "I'm the standard model, Zachary. 'Fun' was optional."
    </p>
    <source>Zot and Peabody, in ZOT! #1</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q269">
    <p>
      Guards! Guards! Stop this madman! He's turning everyone into monkeys!
    </p>
    <source>A sudden intrusion, in ZOT! #1</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q270">
    <p>
      "My, how you've grown!"
    </p>
    <p>
      "C'mon, it's only been a week and a half!"
    </p>
    <source>Uncle Max and Zot, in ZOT! #2</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q271">
    <p>
      "How about you -- what're you up to?"
    </p>
    <p>
      "Issue #3."
    </p>
    <source>Vic and Zot, in ZOT! #3</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q272">
    <p>
      Y'see, I figure I've got two choices at my stage. I can try to make my
      world grow bigger, or I can let it get smaller -- and if I don't do
      the one then the other's gonna happen in time...
    </p>
    <source>Uncle Max, in ZOT! #3</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q273">
    <p>
      I'm sorry I became abusive just now ... calling you worms... I was
      just speaking relatively, you understand.
    </p>
    <source>Dekko, in ZOT! #3</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation id="q274">
    <p>
      "Ah, the stench of evil is about this place!"
    </p>
    <p>
      "Actually, I think that's air-freshener."
    </p>
    <source>Prince Drufus and Vic, in ZOT! #4</source>
  </quotation>

</quotations>
