<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE quotations [
  <!ENTITY agrave "&#224;"> 
  <!ENTITY euml   "&#235;"> <!-- latin small letter e with diaeresis -->
  <!ENTITY iuml   "&#239;"> <!-- latin small letter i with diaeresis -->
  <!ENTITY ouml   "&#246;"> <!-- latin small letter o with diaeresis -->
]>
<?xml-stylesheet href="http://www.amk.ca/qel/qel.css"?>

<quotations xmlns="http://www.amk.ca/qel/"
            xmlns:rdf='http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#'>
  <title>Quotations from H.P. Lovecraft</title>
  <editor>A.M. Kuchling</editor>
  <description>Quotations from H.P. Lovecraft's works and letters.</description>
  <!-- Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike license -->
  <rdf:RDF xmlns="http://web.resource.org/cc/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
    <Work rdf:about="">
       <dc:type rdf:resource="http://purl.org/dc/dcmitype/Text" />
       <license rdf:resource="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/" />
    </Work>

    <License rdf:about="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/">
       <permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Reproduction" />
       <permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Distribution" />
       <requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Notice" />
       <requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Attribution" />
       <permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/DerivativeWorks" />
       <requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/ShareAlike" />
    </License>

    </rdf:RDF>


<!-- Fiction (arranged in chronological order) -->

<quotation date="1919"><p>
My opinion of my whole experience varies from time to time.  In broad
daylight, and at most seasons I am apt to think the greater  part of
it a mere dream; but sometimes in the autumn, about two in the morning
when winds and animals howl dismally, there comes from inconceivable
depths below a damnable suggestions of rhythmical throbbing ... and I
feel that the transition of Juan Romero was a terrible one indeed.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The Transition of Juan Romero"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
There be those who say that things and places have souls, and there be
those who say they have not; I dare not say, myself, but I will tell
of The Street.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The Street"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
But are not the dreams of poets and the tales of travellers
notoriously false?
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The Street"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
In London there is a man who screams when the church bells ring.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The Descendant"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1917"><p>
Men of broader intellect know that there is no sharp distinction
betwixt the real and the unreal... 
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The Tomb"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1917"><p>
I have dwelt ever in realms apart from the visible world; spending my
youth and adolescence in ancient and little-known books, and in
roaming the fields and groves of the region near my ancestral home.  I
do not think that what I read in these books or saw in these fields
and groves was exactly what other boys read and saw there; but of this
I must say little, since detailed speech would but confirm those cruel
slanders upon my intellect which I sometimes overhear from the
whispers of the stealthy attendants around me.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The Tomb"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1918"><p>
Just before dawn Arcturus winks ruddily from above the cemetery on the
low hillock, and Coma Berenices shimmers weirdly afar off in the
mysterious east; but still the Pole Star leers down from the same
place in the black vault, winking hideously like an insane watching
eye which strives to convey some strange message, yet recalls nothing
save that it once had a message to convey.  Sometimes, when it is
cloudy, I can sleep.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"Polaris"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1919"><p>
Sometimes I believe that this less material life  is our truer life,
and that our vain presence on the terraqueous globe is itself the
secondary or merely virtual phenomenon.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"Beyond The Wall of Sleep"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1919"><p>
But more wonderful than the lore of old men and the lore of books is
the secret lore of ocean.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The White Ship"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1919"><p>
Blue, green, grey, white, or black; 
smooth, ruffled, or mountainous; that ocean is not silent.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The White Ship"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1919"><p>
Ocean is more ancient than the mountains, and freighted with the memories and the dreams of Time.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
    <source>"The White Ship"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1919"><p>
In the land of Sona-Nyl there is neither time nor space, neither suffering nor death.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
    <source>"The White Ship"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1919"><p>
I yearned mightily to enter this fascinating yet repellent city, and
besought the bearded man to land me at the stone pier  by the huge
carven gate Akariel; but he gently denied my wish, saying: "Into
Thalarion, the City of a Thousand Wonders, many have passed but none
returned.  Therein walk only daemons and mad things that are no longer
men,  and the streets are white with the unburied bones of those who
have looked upon the eidolon Lathi, that reigns over the city."
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The White Ship"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1920"><p>
For the cat is cryptic, and close to Aegyptus, and bearer of tales
from forgotten cities in Mero&euml; and Ophir.  He is the kin of the
jungle's lords, and heir to the secrets of hoary and sinister Africa.
The Sphinx is his cousin, and he speaks her language; but he is more
ancient than the Sphinx, and remembers that which she hath forgotten.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The Cats of Ulthar"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1920"><p>
Very sleek and fat did the cats appear, and sonorous with purring content.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The Cats of Ulthar"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1920"><p>
But he was unmoved, and cried: "If I am mad, it is mercy!  May the
gods pity the man who in his callousness can remain sane to the
hideous end!"
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The Temple"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1920"><p>
Life is a hideous thing, and from the background behind what we know
of it peer daemoniacal hints of truth which make it sometimes a
thousandfold more hideous.   Science, already oppressive with its
shocking revelations, will perhaps be the ultimate exterminator of our
human species -- if separate species we be -- for its reserve of
unguessed horrors could never be borne by mortal brains if loosed upon
the world.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"Facts Concerning the Late Arthur Jermyn and His Family"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1920"><p>
If we knew what we are, we should do as Sir Arthur Jermyn did; and
Arthur Jermyn soaked himself in oil and set fire to his clothing one night.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"Facts Concerning the Late Arthur Jermyn and His Family"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1920"><p>
Kuranes was not modern, and did not think like others who wrote.
Whilst they strove to strip from life its embroidered robes of myth,
and to shew in naked ugliness the foul thing that is reality, Kuranes
sought for beauty alone.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"Celepha&iuml;s"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1920"><p>
There are not many persons who know what wonders are opened to them in
the stories and visions of their youth; for when as children we learn
and dream, we think but half-formed thoughts, and when as men we try
to remember, we are dulled and prosaic with the poison of life.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"Celepha&iuml;s"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1920"><p>
But some of us awake in the night with strange phantasms of enchanted
hills and gardens, of fountains that sing in the sun, of golden cliffs
overhanging murmuring seas, of plains that stretch down to sleeping
cities of bronze and stone, and of shadowy companies of heroes that
ride caparisoned white horses along the edges of thick forests; and
then we know that we have looked back through the ivory gates into
that world of wonder which was ours before we were wise and unhappy.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"Celepha&iuml;s"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1920"><p>
That Crawford Tillinghast should ever have studied science and
philosophy was a mistake.  These things should be left to the frigid
and impersonal investigator, for they offer two equally tragic
alternatives to the man of feeling and action; despair if he fail in
his quest, and terrors unutterable  and unimaginable if he succeed.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"From Beyond"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1920"><p>
We shall see that at which dogs howl in the dark, and that at which
cats prick up their ears after midnight.  
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"From Beyond"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1920"><p>
I have harnessed the shadows that
stride from world to world to sow death and madness... 
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"From Beyond"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1920"><p>
Searchers after horror haunt strange, far places.  
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
    <source>"The Picture in the House"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1920"><p>
 For them are the
   catacombs of Ptolemais, and the carven mausolea of the nightmare
   countries. They climb to the moonlit towers of ruined Rhine castles,
   and falter down black cobwebbed steps beneath the scattered stones of
   forgotten cities in Asia. The haunted wood and the desolate mountain
   are their shrines, and they linger around the sinister monoliths on
   uninhabited islands. But the true epicure in the terrible, to whom a
   new thrill of unutterable ghastliness is the chief end and
   justification of existence, esteems most of all the ancient, lonely
   farmhouses of backwoods New England; for there the dark elements of
   strength, solitude, grotesqueness and ignorance combine to form the
   perfection of the hideous.
 </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
    <source>"The Picture in the House"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1920"><p>
By necessity practical and by philosophy stern, these folk were not
beautiful in their sins.  Erring as all mortals must, they were forced
by their rigid code  to seek concealment above all else; so that they
came to use less and less taste in what they concealed.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
    <source>"The Picture in the House"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1920"><p>
Only the silent, sleepy, staring houses in the backwoods can tell all
that has lain hidden since the early days; and they are not
communicative, being loath to shake off the drowsiness which helps
them forget.  Sometimes one feels that it would be merciful to tear
down these houses, for they must often dream.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
    <source>"The Picture in the House"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1920"><p>
Queer haow a <em>cravin'</em> gits a holt on ye -- As ye love the
Almighty, young man, don't tell nobody, but I swar ter Gawd thet
picter begun ta make me <em>hungry fer victuals I couldn't raise nor
buy</em>  -- here, set still, what's ailin' ye? ...
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
    <source>"The Picture in the House"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1920"><p>
These folk say that on a table in a bare room on the ground floor are
many peculiar bottles, in each a small piece of lead suspended
pendulum-wise from a string.  And they say that the Terrible Old Man
talks to these bottles, addressing them by such names as Jack,
Scar-Face, Long Tom, Spanish Joe, Peters, and Mate Ellis, and that
whenever he speaks to a bottle the little lead pendulum within makes
certain definite vibrations as if in answer.  Those who have watched
the tall, lean, Terrible Old Man in these peculiar conversations, do
not watch him again.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
    <source>"The Terrible Old Man"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1920"><p>
I recall that the people went about with pale and worried faces, and
whispered warnings and prophecies which no one dared consciously
repeat or acknowledge to himself that he had heard. A sense of
monstrous guilt was upon the land, and out of the abysses between the
stars swept chill currents that made men shiver in dark and lonely
places.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"Nyarlathotep"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1920"><p>
   I  remember  when Nyarlathotep came to my city the great, the old, the
   terrible  city of unnumbered crimes. 
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"Nyarlathotep"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1921"><p>
"That is not dead which can eternal lie / And with strange aeons even
death may die."
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
    <source>Quoting the <cite>Necronomicon</cite>, in "The Nameless City"</source>
<!-- Also cited in "The Call of Cthulhu"-->
</quotation>

<quotation date="1921"><p>
Wherefore do ye toil; is it not that ye may live and be happy?
And if ye toil only that ye may toil more, when shall happiness find
you?  Ye toil to live, but is not life made of beauty and song? ... 
Toil without song is like a weary journey without an end.  Were not
death more pleasing?
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The Quest of Iranon"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1921"><p>
Unhappy is he to whom the memories of childhood bring only fear and sadness.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
    <source>"The Outsider"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1921"><p>
Despite my most careful searches and investigations, I have never
since been able to find the Rue d'Auseil.  But I am not wholly sorry;
either for this or for the loss in undreamable abysses of the closely
written sheets which alone could have explained the music of Erich Zann.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
    <source>"The Music of Erich Zann"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1921"><p>
Memories and possibilities are ever more hideous than realities. 
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
    <source>"Herbert West -- Re-Animator"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1921"><p>
I could not but feel that some  noxious marine mind had declared a war
of extermination upon all the solid ground, perhaps abetted by the
angry sky. 
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft and Winifred Virginia Jackson</author>
  <source>"The Crawling Chaos"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1921"><p>
And when the smoke cleared away, and I sought to look upon the earth,
I beheld against the background of cold, humorous stars only the
dying sun and the pale mournful planets searching for their sister.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft and Winifred Virginia Jackson</author>
  <source>"The Crawling Chaos"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1921"><p>
   When  the  last  days  were upon me, and the ugly trifles of existence
   began  to  drive  me  to  madness  like  the small drops of water that
   torturers  let fall ceaselessly upon one spot of their victim's body, I
   loved  the irradiate refuge of sleep. 
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"Ex Oblivione"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1921"><p>
... for doubt and secrecy are the lure of lures,
   and  no  new horror can be more terrible than the daily torture of the
   commonplace.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"Ex Oblivione"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1922"><p>
It is uncommon to fire all six shots of a revolver with great
suddenness when one would probably be sufficient, but many things in
the life of Herbert West were uncommon.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"Herbert West--Reanimator"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1922"><p>
It is natural that such a thing as a dead man's scream should give
horror, for it is obviously not a pleasing or ordinary occurrence; but
I was used  to similar experiences, hence suffered on this occasion
only because of a particular circumstance.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"Herbert West--Reanimator"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1922"><p>
... West had emerged with a soul calloused and seared, and a hardened
eye which sometimes glanced with a kind of hideous and calculating
appraisal at men of especially sensitive brain and especially vigorous
physique.  Toward the last I became acutely afraid of West, for he
began to look at me that way.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"Herbert West--Reanimator"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1922"><p>
Their outlines were human, semi-human, fractionally human, and not
human at all -- the horde was grotesquely heterogeneous.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"Herbert West--Reanimator"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1922"><p>
They imply that I am either a madman or a murderer -- probably I am
mad.  But I might not be mad if those accursed tomb-legions had not
been so silent.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"Herbert West--Reanimator"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1922"><p>
Men of learning suspect it little, and ignore it mostly.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"Hypnos"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1922"><p>
Among the agonies of these after days is that chief of torments --
inarticulateness.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"Hypnos"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1922"><p>
There were nauseous musical instruments, stringed, brass, and
wood-wind, on which St. John and I sometimes produced dissonances of
exquisite morbidity and cacodaemoniacal ghastliness ...
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The Hound"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1922"><p>
We were no vulgar ghouls, but worked only under certain conditions of
mood, landscape, environment, weather, season, and moonlight. 
These pastimes were to us the most exquisite form of aesthetic
expression, and we gave their details a fastidious technical care.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The Hound"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1922"><p>
Alien it indeed was to all art and literature which sane
   and balanced readers know, but we recognized it as the thing hinted of
   in the forbidden Necronomicon of the mad Arab Abdul Alhazred...
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>The first mention of the Necronomicon, in "The Hound"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1922"><p>
As we hastened from that abhorrent spot, the stolen amulet in
St. John's pocket, we thought we saw the bats descend in a body to the
earth we had so lately rifled, as if seeking for some cursed and
unholy nourishment.  But the autumn moon shone weak and pale, and we
could not be sure.
So, too, as we sailed the next day away from
Holland to our home, we thought we heard  the faint distant baying of
some gigantic hound in the background.
But the autumn wind moaned sad and wan, and we
could not be sure. 
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The Hound"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1922"><p>
History had led me to this archaic grave.  History, indeed, was all I
had after everything else ended in mocking Satanism.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The Lurking Fear"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1923"><p>
Besides, he added, my constant talk about "unnamable" and
"unmentionable" things was a very puerile device, quite in keeping
with my lowly standing as an author.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The Unnamable"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1923"><p>
We know things, he said, only through our five senses or our religious
intuitions; wherefore it is quite impossible to refer to any object or
spectacle which cannot be clearly depicted by the solid definitions of
fact or the correct doctrines of theology -- preferably those of the
Congregationalists, with whatever modifications tradition and Sir
Arthur Conan Doyle may supply.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The Unnamable"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1923"><p>
The witchcraft terror is a horrible ray of light on what was stewing
in men's crushed brains, but even that is a trifle.
There was no beauty; no freedom -- we can see that from the
architectural and household remains, and the poisonous sermons of the
cramped divines.  And inside that rusted iron strait-jacket lurked
gibbering hideousness, perversion, and diabolism.  Here, truly, was
the apotheosis of the unnamable.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The Unnamable"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1923"><p>
I was far from home, and the spell of the eastern sea was upon me.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The Festival"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1923"><p>
It was the Yuletide, that men call Christmas though they know in their
hearts it is older than Bethlehem and Babylon, older than Memphis and mankind.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The Festival"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1923"><p>
I was the only one who came back that night to the old fishing town as
legend bade, for only the poor and the lonely remember.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The Festival"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1923"><p>
Out of the unimaginable blackness beyond the gangrenous glare of that
cold flame, out of the Tartarean leagues through which that oily river
rolled uncanny, unheard, and unsuspected, there flopped rhythmically a
horde of tame, trained, hybrid winged things that no sound eye  could
ever wholly grasp, or sound brain ever wholly remember.  They were not
altogether crows, nor moles, nor buzzards, nor ants, nor vampire bats,
nor decomposed human beings, but something I cannot and must not recall.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The Festival"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1923"><p>
"The nethermost caverns," wrote the mad Arab, "are not for the
fathoming of eyes that see; for their marvels are strange and
terrific.  Cursed the ground where dead thoughts live new and oddly
bodied, and evil the mind that is held by no head."
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The Festival", quoting the <cite>Necronomicon</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1923"><p>
For it is of old rumour that the soul of the devil-bought hastes not
from his charnel clay, but fats and instructs <em>the very worm that
gnaws</em>; till out of corruption horrid life springs, and the dull
scavengers of earth wax crafty to vex it and swell monstrous to plague
it.  Great holes secretly are digged where earth's pores ought to
suffice, and things have learnt to walk that ought to crawl.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The Festival", quoting the <cite>Necronomicon</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1923"><p>
Through all this horror my cat stalked unperturbed.  Once I saw him
monstrously perched atop a mountain of bones, and wondered at the
secrets that might lie behind his yellow eyes.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
    <source>"The Rats in the Walls"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1923"><p>
Ultimate horror often paralyses memory in a merciful way.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
    <source>"The Rats in the Walls"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1923"><p>
Prying curiosity means death.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
    <source>"The Rats in the Walls"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1923"><p>
They must know it was the rats; the slithering, scurrying rats whose
scampering will never let me sleep; the daemon rats that race behind
the padding in this room and beckon me down to greater horrors than I
have ever known; the rats they can never hear; the rats, the rats in
the walls.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
    <source>"The Rats in the Walls"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1924"><p>
I dreamed that I was in the grasp of a great and horrible paw; a
yellow, hairy, five-clawed paw which had reached out of the earth to
crush and engulf me.  And when I stopped to reflect what the paw was,
it seemed to me that it was Egypt.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"Under the Pyramids"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1924"><p>
But I survived, and I know it was only a dream.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"Under the Pyramids"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1924"><p>
From even the greatest of horrors irony is seldom absent.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The Shunned House"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1924"><p>
We were not, as I have said, in any sense childishly superstitious,
but scientific study and reflection had taught us that the known
universe of three dimensions embraces the merest fraction of the whole
cosmos of substance and energy. In this case an overwhelming
preponderance of evidence from numerous authentic sources pointed to
the tenacious existence of certain forces of great power and, so far
as the human point of view is concerned, exceptional malignancy. 
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The Shunned House"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1924"><p>
There are horrors beyond horrors, and this was one of those nuclei of
all dreamable hideousness which the cosmos saves to blast an accursed
and unhappy few. 
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The Shunned House"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1924"><p>
The next spring no more pale grass and strange weeds came up in the
shunned house's terraced garden, and shortly afterward Carrington
Harris rented the place. It it still spectral, but its strangeness
fascinates me, and I shall find mixed with my relief a queer regret
when it is torn down to make way for a tawdry shop or vulgar apartment
building. The barren old trees in the yard have begun to bear small,
sweet apples, and last year the birds nested in their gnarled boughs. 
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The Shunned House"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1925"><p>
This was a
simple explanation which everyone could understand, and because Malone
was not a simple person he perceived that he had better let it suffice.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The Horror at Red Hook"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1925"><p>
More people enter Red Hook than leave it -- or at least, than leave it
by the landward side -- and those who are not loquacious are the
likeliest to leave.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The Horror at Red Hook"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1925"><p>
I saw him on a sleepless night when I was walking desperately to save
my soul and my vision.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"He"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1925"><p>
My coming to New York had been a mistake; for whereas I had looked for
poignant wonder and inspiration in the teeming labyrinths of ancient
streets that twist endlessly from forgotten courts and squares and
waterfronts to courts and squares and waterfronts equally forgotten,
and in the Cyclopean modern towers and pinnacles that rise blackly
Babylonian under waning moons, I had found instead only a sense of
horror and oppression which threatened to master, paralyse, and
annihilate me.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"He"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1925"><p>
So instead of the poems I had hoped for, there came only a shuddering
blankness and ineffable loneliness; and I saw at last a fearful truth
which no one had ever dared to breathe before -- the unwhisperable
secret of secrets -- that fact that this city of stone and stridor is
not a sentient perpetuation of Old New York as London is of Old London
and Paris of Old Paris, but that it is in fact quite dead, its
sprawling body imperfectly embalmed and infested with queer animate
things which have nothing to do with it as it was in life.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"He"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1926"><p>
Then one summer there came a philosopher into Kingsport.  His name was
Thomas Olney, and he taught ponderous things in a college by
Narragansett Bay.  With stout wife and romping children he came, and
his eyes were weary with seeing the same things for many years, and
thinking the same well-disciplined thoughts.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The Strange High House in the Mist"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1926"><p>
Then Olney saw lingering against the translucent squares of each of
the little dim windows in succession a queer black outline as the
caller moved inquisitively about before leaving; and he was glad his
host had not answered the knocking.  For there are strange objects in
the great abyss, and the seeker of dreams must take care not to stir
up or meet the wrong ones.  
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The Strange High House in the Mist"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1926"><p>
Then the shadows began to gather; first little furtive ones under the
table, and then bolder ones in the dark panelled corners.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The Strange High House in the Mist"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1926"><p>
And ever since that hour, through dull dragging years of greyness and
weariness, the philosopher has laboured and eaten and slept and done
uncomplaining the suitable deeds of a citizen.  Not any more does he
long for the magic of farther hills, or sigh for secrets that peer
like green reefs from a bottomless sea.  The sameness of his days no
longer gives him sorrow, and well-disciplined thoughts have grown
enough for his imagination.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The Strange High House in the Mist"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1926"><p>
And they do not wish quaint Kingsport with its climbing lanes and
archaic gables to drag listless down the years while voice by voice
the laughing chorus grows stronger and wilder in that unknown and
terrible eyrie where mists and the dreams of mists stop to rest on
their way from the sea to the skies. 
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The Strange High House in the Mist"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1926"><p>
All these things, however, the Elder Ones only may decide; and
meanwhile the morning mist still comes up by that lonely vertiginous
peak with the steep ancient house, that grey low-eaved house where
none is seen but where evening brings furtive lights while the north
wind tells of strange revels.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The Strange High House in the Mist"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1926"><p>
And when tales fly thick in the grottoes of tritons, and conches in
seaweed cities blow wild tunes learned from the Elder Ones, then great
eager vapours flock to heaven laden with lore; and Kingsport, nestling
uneasy on its lesser cliffs below that awesome hanging sentinel of
rock, sees oceanward only a mystic whiteness, as if the cliff's rim
were the rim of all earth, and the solemn bells of the buoys tolled
free in the aether of faery.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The Strange High House in the Mist"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1926"><p>
The only saving grace of the present is that it's too damned stupid
to question the past very closely.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
    <source>"Pickman's Model"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1926"><p>
... another conception somehow shocked me more than all the rest --
a scene in an unknown vault, where scores of the beasts crowded about
one who held a well-known Boston guide-book and was evidently reading
aloud.  All were pointing to a certain passage, and every face seemed
so distorted with epileptic and reverberant laughter that I almost
thought I heard the fiendish echoes.  The title of the picture was,
"Holmes, Lowell, and Longfellow Lie Buried in Mount Auburn".
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
    <source>"Pickman's Model"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1926"><p>
The most merciful thing in the world, I think, is the inability of the
human mind to correlate all its contents.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
    <source>"The Call of Cthulhu"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1926"><p>
We live on a placid island of ignorance in the midst of black seas of
infinity, and it was not meant that we should voyage far.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
    <source>"The Call of Cthulhu"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1926"><p>
The sciences, each straining in its own direction, have hitherto
harmed us little; but some day the piecing together of dissociated
knowledge will open up such terrifying vistas of reality, and of our
frightful position therein, that we shall either go mad from the
revelation or flee from the deadly light into the peace and safety of
a new dark age.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
    <source>"The Call of Cthulhu"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1926"><p>
That glimpse, like all dread glimpses of truth, flashed out from an
accidental piecing together of separated things -- in this case an old
newspaper item and the notes of a dead professor.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
    <source>"The Call of Cthulhu"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1926"><p>
Above these apparent hieroglyphics was a figure of evidently pictorial
intent, though its impressionistic execution forbade a very clear idea
of its nature.    It seemed to be a sort of monster, or symbol
representing a monster, of a form which only a diseased fancy could
conceive.  If I say that my somewhat extravagant imagination yielded
simultaneous pictures of an octopus, a dragon, and a human caricature,
I shall not be unfaithful to the spirit of the thing.  A pulpy,
tentacled head surmounted a grotesque  and scaly body with rudimentary
wings, but it was the <em>general outline</em> of the whole which made
it most shockingly frightful.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
    <source>"The Call of Cthulhu"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1926"><p>
What seemed to be the main document  was headed "CTHULHU CULT" in
characters painstakingly printed to avoid the erroneous reading of a
word so unheard-of.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
    <source>"The Call of Cthulhu"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1926"><p>
Ph'nglui mglw'nafh Cthulhu R'lyeh wgah'nagl fhtagn.
("In his house at R'lyeh dead Cthulhu waits dreaming.")
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
    <source>"The Call of Cthulhu"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1926"><p>
When the stars were right, They could plunge from world to world
through the sky; but when the stars were wrong, They could not live.
But although They no longer lived, They would never really die.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
    <source>"The Call of Cthulhu"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1926"><p>
That cult would never die till the stars came right again,  and the
secret priests would take great Cthulhu from His tomb to revive His
subjects and resume His rule of earth.  The time would be easy to
know, for then mankind would have become as the Great Old Ones; free
and wild  and beyond good and evil, with laws and morals thrown aside
and all men shouting and killing and revelling in joy.  
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
    <source>"The Call of Cthulhu"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1926"><p>
I now felt gnawing at my vitals that dark terror which
will never leave me till I, too, am at rest; "accidentally" or
otherwise. 
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
    <source>"The Call of Cthulhu"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1926"><p>
It is a mistake to fancy that horror is associated inextricably with
darkness, silence, and solitude.  I found it in the glare of
mid-afternoon, in the clangour of a metropolis, and in the teeming
midst of a shabby and commonplace rooming-house with a prosaic
landlady and two stalwart men by my side.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
    <source>"Cool Air"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1926"><p>
Calm, lasting beauty comes only in dream, and this solace the world
had thrown away when in its worship of the real it threw away the
secrets of childhood and innocence. 
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The Silver Key"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1926"><p>
It was after this that he cultivated deliberate illusion, and
dabbled in the notions of the bizarre and the eccentric as an antidote
for the commonplace. Most of these, however, soon shewed their poverty
and barrenness; and he saw that the popular doctrines of occultism are
as dry and inflexible as those of science, yet without even the
slender palliative of truth to redeem them. 
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The Silver Key"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1926"><p>
Gross stupidity,
falsehood, and muddled thinking are not dream; and form no escape from
life to a mind trained above their own level. 
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The Silver Key"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1926"><p>
There are twists of time and space, of vision and reality, which only
a dreamer can divine; and from what I know of Carter I think he has
merely found a way to traverse these mazes. Whether or not he will
ever come back, I cannot say. 
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The Silver Key"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1926"><p>
 Certainly, I look forward impatiently to the sight of that great
 silver key, for in its cryptical arabesques there may stand
 symbolised all the aims and mysteries of a blindly impersonal
 cosmos. 
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The Silver Key"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1927"><p>
It was nothing of this earth, but a piece of the great outside; and as
such dowered with outside properties and obedient to outside laws.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
    <source>"The Colour Out of Space"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1927"><p>
No sane wholesome colours were anywhere to be seen except in the green
grass and leafage; but everywhere those hectic and prismatic variants
of some diseased, underlying primary tone without a place among the
known tints of earth.  The Dutchman's breeches became a thing of
sinister menace, and the bloodroots grew insolent in their chromatic
perversion. 
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
    <source>"The Colour Out of Space"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1927"><p>
One may picture him yet as he was in those days; tall, slim, and
blond, with studious eyes and a slight stoop, dressed somewhat
carelessly, and giving a dominant impression of harmless awkwardness
rather than attractiveness. 
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The Case of Charles Dexter Ward"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1927"><p>
The nurse used to stop and sit on the benches of Prospect Terrace to
chat with policemen; and one of the child's first memories was of the
great westward sea of hazy roofs and domes and steeples and far hills
which he saw one winter afternoon from that great railed embankment,
all violet and mystic against a fevered, apocalyptic sunset of reds
and golds and purples and curious greens. The vast marble dome of the
State House stood out in massive silhouette, its crowning statue
haloed fantastically by a break in one of the tinted stratus clouds
that barred the flaming sky. 
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The Case of Charles Dexter Ward"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1927"><p>
I say to you againe, doe not call up Any that you can not put downe;
by the Which I meane, Any that can in Turne call up somewhat against
you, whereby your Powerfullest Devices may not be of use. Ask of the
Lesser, lest the Greater shall not wish to Answer, and shall commande
more than you. 
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>A letter from Simon Orne, in "The Case of Charles Dexter Ward"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1927"><p>
Just beyond Elder Snow's church some of the men turned back to take a
parting look at Providence lying outspread under the early spring
stars. Steeples and gables rose dark and shapely, and salt breezes
swept up gently from the cove north of the Bridge. Vega was climbing
above the great hill across the water, whose crest of trees was broken
by the roof-line of the unfinished College edifice. At the foot of
that hill, and along the narrow mounting lanes of its side, the old
town dreamed; Old Providence, for whose safety and sanity so monstrous
and colossal a blasphemy was about to be wiped out. 
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The Case of Charles Dexter Ward"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1927"><p>
Old Providence! It was this place and the mysterious forces of its
long, continuous history which had brought him into being, and which
had drawn him back toward marvels and secrets whose boundaries no
prophet might fix. Here lay the arcana, wondrous or dreadful as the
case might be, for which all his years of travel and application had
been preparing him. 
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The Case of Charles Dexter Ward"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1927"><p>
A taxicab whirled him through Post Office Square with its glimpse of
the river, the old Market House, and the head of the bay, and up the
steep curved slope of Waterman Street to Prospect, where the vast
gleaming dome and sunset-flushed Ionic columns of the Christian
Science Church beckoned northward. Then eight squares past the fine
old estates his childish eyes had known, and the quaint brick
sidewalks so often trodden by his youthful feet. And at last the
little white overtaken farmhouse on the right, on the left the classic
Adam porch and stately facade of the great brick house where he was
born. It was twilight, and Charles Dexter Ward had come home.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The Case of Charles Dexter Ward"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1927"><p>
Memory sometimes makes merciful deletions.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The Case of Charles Dexter Ward"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1927"><p>
"I have brought to light a monstrous abnormality, but I did it for the
sake of knowledge. Now for the sake of all life and Nature you must
help me thrust it back into the dark again."
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>Charles Dexter Ward's letter, in "The Case of Charles Dexter Ward"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1927"><p>
That Thomas Sabin's Boston coach was "damn'd uncomfortable" old
letters may well have told; but what healthy antiquarian could recall
how the creaking of Epenetus Olney's new signboard (the gaudy crown he
set up after he took to calling his tavern the Crown Coffee House) was
exactly like the first few notes of the new jazz piece all the radios
in Pawtuxet were playing? 
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The Case of Charles Dexter Ward"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1927"><p>
Mystery hung about it as clouds about a fabulous unvisited mountain;
and as Carter stood breathless and expectant on that balustraded
parapet there swept up to him the poignancy and suspense of
almost-vanished memory, the pain of lost things and the maddening need
to place again what once had been an awesome and momentous place. 
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The Dream-Quest of Unknown Kadath"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1927"><p>
In the tunnels of that twisted wood, whose low prodigious oaks twine
groping boughs and shine dim with the phosphorescence of strange
fungi, dwell the furtive and secretive zoogs; who know many obscure
secrets of the dream-world and a few of the waking world, since the
wood at two places touches the lands of men, though it would be
disastrous to say where. 
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The Dream-Quest of Unknown Kadath"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1927"><p>
There he would turn sharply aside, for at that spot a mighty slab of
stone rests on the forest floor; and those who have dared approach it
say that it bears an iron ring three feet wide. Remembering the
archaic circle of great mossy rocks, and what it was possibly set up
for, the Zoogs do not pause near that expansive slab with its huge
ring; for they realise that all which is forgotten need not
necessarily be dead, and they would not like to see the slab rise
slowly and deliberately.  
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
    <source>"The Dream Quest of Unknown Kadath"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1927"><p>
So, Atal said, it would be much better to let all gods alone except in tactful prayers.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
    <source>"The Dream Quest of Unknown Kadath"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1927"><p>
A yowl now came from the farther peak, and the old leader paused
abruptly in his conversation. It was one of the army's outposts,
stationed on the highest of the mountains to watch the one foe which
Earth's cats fear; the very large and peculiar cats from Saturn, who
for some reason have not been oblivious of the charm of our moon's
dark side. They are leagued by treaty with the evil toad-things, and
are notoriously hostile to our earthly cats; so that at this juncture
a meeting would have been a somewhat grave matter.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The Dream-Quest of Unknown Kadath"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1927"><p>
But Carter preferred to look at them
than at his captors, which were indeed shocking and uncouth black
beings with smooth, oily, whale-like surfaces, unpleasant horns that
curved inward toward each other, bat-wings whose beating made no
sound, ugly prehensile paws, and barbed tails that lashed needlessly
and disquietingly. And worst of all, they never spoke or laughed, and
never smiled because they had no faces at all to smile with, but only
a suggestive blankness where a face ought to be. All they ever did was
clutch and fly and tickle; that was the way of night-gaunts. 
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The Dream-Quest of Unknown Kadath"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1927"><p>
There, on a tombstone of 1768 stolen from the Granary Burying Ground
in Boston, sat a ghoul which was once the artist Richard Upton
Pickman.  
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The Dream-Quest of Unknown Kadath"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1927"><p>
For a ghoul is a ghoul, and at best an unpleasant companion for man.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The Dream-Quest of Unknown Kadath"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1927"><p>
Carter was there to greet them, and the sight of shapely, wholesome
cats was indeed good for his eyes after the things he had seen and
walked with in the abyss. 
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The Dream-Quest of Unknown Kadath"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1927"><p>
A blessed haze lies upon all this region, wherein is held a little
more of the sunlight than other places hold, and a little more of the
summer's humming music of birds and bees; so that men walk through it
as through a faery place, and feel greater joy and wonder than they
ever afterward remember. 
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The Dream-Quest of Unknown Kadath"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1927"><p>
Once a lookout reported fires on the hills to the east, but the sleepy
captain said they had better not be looked at too much, since it was
highly uncertain just who or what had lit them. 
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The Dream-Quest of Unknown Kadath"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1927"><p>
It seems that these men have an aura not of earth about them, though
that is not the reason why no cat will sail on their ships. The reason
for this is that Inquanok holds shadows which no cat can endure, so
that in all that cold twilight realm there is never a cheering purr or
a homely mew. 
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The Dream-Quest of Unknown Kadath"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1927"><p>
Then suddenly the clouds thinned and the stars shone spectrally
above. All below was still black, but those pallid beacons in the sky
seemed alive with a meaning and directiveness they had never possessed
elsewhere. It was not that the figures of the constellations were
different, but that the same familiar shapes now revealed a
significance they had formerly failed to make plain. Everything
focussed toward the north; every curve and asterism of the glittering
sky became part of a vast design whose function was to hurry first the
eye and then the whole observer onward to some secret and terrible
goal of convergence beyond the frozen waste that stretched endlessly
ahead. 
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The Dream-Quest of Unknown Kadath"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1927"><p>
It was a song, but not the song of any voice. Night and the spheres
sang it, and it was old when space and Nyarlathotep and the Other
Gods were born.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The Dream-Quest of Unknown Kadath"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1928"><p>
Then too, the natives are mortally afraid of the numerous
whippoorwills which grow vocal on warm nights.  It is vowed that the
birds are psychopomps lying in wait for the souls of the dying, 
and that they time their eerie cries in unison with the sufferer's
struggling breath.  If they can catch the fleeing soul when it leaves
the body, they instantly flutter away chittering in daemoniac
laughter; but if they fail, they subside gradually into a disappointed
silence. 
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
    <source>"The Dunwich Horror"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1928"><p>
The Old Ones were, the Old Ones are, and the Old Ones shall be.  Not
in the spaces we know, but <em>between</em> them, They walk serene and
primal, undimensioned and to us unseen.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
    <source>Quoting from the <cite>Necronomicon</cite> in 
"The Dunwich Horror"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1928"><p>
Yog-Sothoth knows the gate.  Yog-Sothoth is the gate.  Yog-Sothoth is
the key and guardian of the gate.  Past, present, future, all are one
in Yog-Sothoth.  He knows where the Old Ones broke through of old, and
where They shall break through again.  He knows where They have trod
earth's fields, and where They still tread them, and why no one can
behold Them as They tread.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
    <source>Quoting from the <cite>Necronomicon</cite> in "The Dunwich Horror"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1928"><p>
They walk unseen and foul in lonely places where the Words have been
spoken and the Rites howled through at their Seasons.  The wind
gibbers with Their voices, and the earth mutters with Their
consciousness.  They bend the forest and crush the city, yet may not
forest or city behold the hand that smites.   Kadath in the cold waste
hath known Them, and what man knows Kadath?
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
    <source>Quoting from the <cite>Necronomicon</cite> in "The Dunwich Horror"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1928"><p>
As a foulness shall ye know Them.  Their hand is at your throats,  yet
ye see Them not; and Their habitation is even one with your guarded threshold.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
    <source>Quoting from the <cite>Necronomicon</cite> in "The Dunwich Horror"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1928"><p>
Man rules now where They ruled once; They shall soon rule where man
rules now.  After summer  is winter, and after winter summer.  They
wait patient and potent, for here shall They reign again.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
    <source>Quoting from the <cite>Necronomicon</cite> in "The Dunwich Horror"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1930"><p>
Even the sunlight assumed a supernal glamour, as if some special
atmosphere or exhalation mantled the whole region.  I had seen nothing
like it before save in the magic vistas that sometimes form the
backgrounds of Italian primitives.  Sodoma and Leonardo conceived such
expanses, but only in the distance, and through the vaultings of
Renaissance arcades.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
    <source>"The Whisperer in Darkness"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1930"><p>
Never was a sane man more dangerously close to the arcana of basic
entity -- never was an organic brain nearer to utter annihilation in
the chaos that transcends form and force and symmetry.  
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
    <source>"The Whisperer in Darkness"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1930"><p>
I learned whence Cthulhu <em>first</em> came, and why half the great
temporary stars of history had flared forth.  I guessed -- from hints
which made even my informant pause timidly -- the secret behind the
Magellanic Clouds and globular nebulae, and the black truth veiled by
the immemorial allegory of Tao.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
    <source>"The Whisperer in Darkness"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1930"><p>
The sense of a throwback was all the stronger because I felt
instinctively that the common problem of the Spaniard and myself was
one of such abysmal timelessness -- of such unholy and unearthly
eternity -- that the scant four hundred years between us bulked as
nothing in comparison.    It took no more than a single look  at that
monstrous  and insidious cylinder to make me realize the dizzying
gulfs that yawned between all men of the known earth and the primal
mysteries it represented.  Before that gulf P&agrave;nfilo de
Zamacona and I stood side by side; just as Aristotle and I, or Cheops
and I, might have stood. 
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft and Zealia Bishop</author>
  <source>"The Mound"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1930"><p> 
Never mix up with secret and ultimate horror, young man, if you value
your immortal soul.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft and Zealia Bishop</author>
    <source>"Medusa's Coil"</source>
</quotation>


<quotation date="1931"><p>
Certainly, the terror of a deserted house swells in geometrical rather
than arithmetical progression as houses multiply to form a city of
stark desolation.  The sight of such linked infinities of black,
brooding compartments given over to cobwebs and memories and the
conqueror worm, start up vestigial fears and aversions that not even
the stoutest philosophy can disperse.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
    <source>"The Shadow Over Innsmouth"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1931"><p>
Doubt of the real facts, as I must reveal them, is inevitable; yet if
I suppressed what will seem extravagant and incredible there would be
nothing left.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"At the Mountains of Madness"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1931"><p>
Every incident of that four-and-a-half hour flight is burned into my
recollection because of its crucial position in my life.  It marked my
loss, at the age of fifty-four, of all that peace and balance which
the normal mind possesses through its accustomed conception of
external Nature and Nature's laws.  
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"At the Mountains of Madness"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1931"><p>
I could not help feeling that they were evil things -- mountains of
madness whose farther slopes looked out over some accursed ultimate abyss.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"At the Mountains of Madness"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1931"><p>
We did not mention, I think, their display of the same uneasiness when
sniffing around the queer greenish soapstones and certain other
objects in the disordered region; objects including scientific
instruments, aeroplanes, and machinery both at the camp and at the
boring, whose parts had been loosened, moved, or otherwise tampered
with by winds that must have harboured singular curiosity and investigativeness.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"At the Mountains of Madness"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1931"><p>
There were geometrical forms for which an Euclid could scarcely find a
name -- cones of all degrees of irregularity and truncation; terraces
of every sort of provocative disproportion; shafts with odd bulbous
enlargements; broken columns in curious groups; and five-pointed or
five-ridged arrangements of mad grotesqueness.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"At the Mountains of Madness"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1931"><p>
Imagination could conceive almost anything in connexion with this place.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"At the Mountains of Madness"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1931"><p>
These vertebrates, as well as an infinity of other life forms --
animal and vegetable, marine, terrestrial, and a&euml;rial -- were the
products of unguided evolution acting on life-cells made by the Old
Ones, but escaping beyond their radius of attention. They had been
suffered to develop unchecked because they had not come in conflict
with the dominant beings. Bothersome forms, of course, were
mechanically exterminated. It interested us to see in some of the very
last and most decadent sculptures a shambling, primitive mammal, used
sometimes for food and sometimes as an amusing buffoon by the land
dwellers, whose vaguely simian and human foreshadowings were
unmistakable.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"At the Mountains of Madness"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1931"><p>
Perhaps we were mad -- for have I not said those horrible peaks were
mountains of madness? But I think I can detect something of the same
spirit -- albeit in a less extreme form -- in the men who stalk deadly
beasts through African jungles to photograph them or study their
habits. Half paralyzed with terror though we were, there was
nevertheless fanned within us a blazing flame of awe and curiosity
which triumphed in the end. 
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"At the Mountains of Madness"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1931"><p>
Poor devils! After all, they were not evil things of their kind. They
were the men of another age and another order of being. Nature had
played a hellish jest on them -- as it will on any others that human
madness, callousness, or cruelty may hereafter dig up in that
hideously dead or sleeping polar waste - and this was their tragic
homecoming.
</p><p>
They had not been even savages -- for what indeed had they
done? That awful awakening in the cold of an unknown epoch -- perhaps
an attack by the furry, frantically barking quadrupeds, and a dazed
defense against them and the equally frantic white simians with the
queer wrappings and paraphernalia ... poor Lake, poor Gedney... and
poor Old Ones! Scientists to the last -- what had they done that we
would not have done in their place? God, what intelligence and
persistence! What a facing of the incredible, just as those carven
kinsmen and forbears had faced things only a little less incredible!
Radiates, vegetables, monstrosities, star spawn -- whatever they had
been, they were men! 
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"At the Mountains of Madness"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1931"><p>
The penguins alone could not have saved us, but in conjunction with
the mist they seem to have done so. 
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"At the Mountains of Madness"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1931"><p>
"South Station Under -- Washington Under -- Park Street
Under-Kendall -- Central -- Harvard -- " The poor fellow was chanting
the familiar stations of the Boston-Cambridge tunnel that burrowed
through our peaceful native soil thousands of miles away in New
England, yet to me the ritual had neither irrelevance nor home
feeling. It had only horror, because I knew unerringly the monstrous,
nefandous analogy that had suggested it. 
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"At the Mountains of Madness"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1931"><p>
It was the utter, objective embodiment of the fantastic novelist's
"thing that should not be"; and its nearest comprehensible analogue is
a vast, onrushing subway train as one sees it from a station platform
-- the great black front looming colossally out of infinite
subterraneous distance, constellated with strangely coloured lights and
filling the prodigious burrow as a piston fills a cylinder. 
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"At the Mountains of Madness"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1931"><p>
The grey half-daylight of the vast circular space sobered us somewhat;
but we did not go near those cached sledges or look again at poor
Gedney and the dog. They have a strange and titanic mausoleum, and I
hope the end of this planet will find them still undisturbed. 
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"At the Mountains of Madness"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1932"><p>
Possibly Gilman ought not to have studied so hard. Non-Euclidean
calculus and quantum physics are enough to stretch any brain; and when
one mixes them with folklore, and tries to trace a strange background
of multi-dimensional reality behind the ghoulish hints of the Gothic
tales and the wild whispers of the chimney-corner, one can hardly
expect to be wholly free from mental tension. 
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The Dreams in the Witch House"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1933"><p>
But he was still content, for at one mighty venture he was to learn
all. Damnation, he reflected, is but a word bandied about by those
whose blindness leads them to condemn all who can see, even with a
single eye. 
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft and E. Hoffman Price</author>
  <source>"Through the Gates of the Silver Key"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1933"><p>
He wondered at the vast conceit of those who had babbled
of the <em>malignant</em> Ancient Ones, as if They could pause from
their everlasting dreams to wreak a wrath on mankind. As well, he thought,
might a mammoth pause to visit frantic vengeance on an angleworm.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft and E. Hoffman Price</author>
  <source>"Through the Gates of the Silver Key"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1933"><p>
The Man of Truth has learned that Illusion is the One Reality, and
that Substance is the Great Imposter.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft and E. Hoffman Price</author>
  <source>"Through the Gates of the Silver Key"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1935"><p>
   If the thing did happen, then man must be prepared to accept notions
   of the cosmos, and of his own place in the seething vortex of time,
   whose merest mention is paralysing. He must, too, be placed on guard
   against a specific, lurking peril which, though it will never engulf
   the whole race, may impose monstrous and unguessable horrors upon
   certain venturesome members of it.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
    <source>"The Shadow Out of Time"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1935"><p>
After man there would be the mighty beetle civilisation, the bodies of
whose members the cream of the Great Race would seize when the
monstrous doom overtook the elder world.  Later, as the earth's span
closed, the transferred minds would again migrate through time and
space --  to another stopping place in the bodies of the bulbous
vegetable entities of Mercury.  But there would be races after them,
clinging pathetically to the cold planet and burrowing to its
horror-filled core, before the utter end.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
    <source>"The Shadow Out of Time"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1935"><p>
   Madness, of course -- but had I not now stumbled into a nighted world
   as mad as I?
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
    <source>"The Shadow Out of Time"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1935"><p>
If the thing were there -- and if I were not dreaming -- the
implications would be quite beyond the power of the human spirit to
bear.  What tormented me most was my momentary inability to feel that
my surroundings were a dream.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
    <source>"The Shadow Out of Time"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1935"><p>
If that abyss and what it held were real, there is no hope.  
Then, all too truly, there lies upon this world of man a mocking and
incredible shadow out of time.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
    <source>"The Shadow Out of Time"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1935"><p>
I did not bring back the metal case that would have been a proof, and
so far those subterrene corridors have not been found.
</p><p>
If the laws of the universe are kind, they will never be found.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
    <source>"The Shadow Out of Time"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1935"><p>
Truly, there are terrible primal arcana of earth which had better be
left unknown and unevoked; dread secrets which have nothing to do with
man, and which man may learn only in exchange  for peace and sanity;
cryptic truths which make the knower evermore an alien among his kind,
and cause him to walk alone on earth.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft and William Lumley</author>
  <source>"The Diary of Alonzo Typer"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1935"><p>
Likewise are there dread survivals of things older and more potent
than man;  things that have blasphemously straggled down through the
aeons to ages never meant for them; monstrous entities  that have lain
sleeping endlessly in incredible crypts and remote caverns, outside
the laws of reason and causation, and ready to be waked by such
blasphemers as shall know their dark forbidden signs and furtive
passwords. 
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft and William Lumley</author>
  <source>"The Diary of Alonzo Typer"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1936"><p>
As the end approaches I feel more kindly toward the things.  In the
scale of cosmic entity who can say which species stands higher, or
more nearly approaches a space-wide organic norm -- theirs or mine?
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft and Kenneth Sterling</author>
  <source>"In the Walls of Eryx"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1936"><p>
Things seen by the inward sight, like those flashing visions which
comes as we drift into the blankness of sleep, are more vivid and
meaningful to us in that form than when we have sought to weld them
with reality.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">R.H. Barlow and H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The Night Ocean"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1936"><p>
Set a pen to a dream, and the colour drains from it.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">R.H. Barlow and H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The Night Ocean"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1936"><p>
In dreams and visions lie the greatest creations of man, for on them
rests no yoke of line or hue.  
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">R.H. Barlow and H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The Night Ocean"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1936"><p>
There were painted women in tinsel  adornments, and bored men who were
no longer young  -- a throng of foolish marionettes perched on the lip
of the ocean-chasm; unseeing, unwilling to see what lay above them and
about, in the multitudinous grandeur of the stars and the leagues of
the night ocean.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">R.H. Barlow and H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The Night Ocean"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1936"><p>
When I reached my high residence I knew that I had passed no one
during the mile's walk from the village, and yet there somehow
lingered an impression that I had been all the while accompanied by
the spirit of the lonely sea.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">R.H. Barlow and H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The Night Ocean"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1936"><p>
It was astonishing the number of useless things people found to do.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">R.H. Barlow and H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The Night Ocean"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1936"><p>
The morning ocean, glimmering with a reflected mist of blue-white cloud
and expanding diamond foam, has the eyes of one who ponders on strange
things; and her intricately woven webs, through which dart a myriad
coloured fishes, hold the air of some great idle thing which will
arise presently from the hoary immemorial chasms and stride upon the
land.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">R.H. Barlow and H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The Night Ocean"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1936"><p>
The sea can bind us to her many moods, whispering to us by the subtle 
token of a shadow or a gleam upon the waves, and hinting in these ways
of her mournfulness or rejoicing.  Always she is remembering old
things, and these memories, though we may not grasp them, are imparted
to us, so that we share her gaiety or remorse.  
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">R.H. Barlow and H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The Night Ocean"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1936"><p>
The ocean ruled my life during the whole of that late summer;
demanding it as recompense for the healing she had brought me.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">R.H. Barlow and H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The Night Ocean"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1936"><p>
There were drownings at the beach that year; and while I heard of
these only casually (such is our indifference to a death which does
not concern us, and to which we are not witness), I knew that 
their details were unsavoury.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">R.H. Barlow and H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The Night Ocean"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1936"><p>
Frequently, in a momentary perception, we feel that a feathery
landscape (for instance), a woman's dress along the curve of a road by
afternoon, or the solidity of a century-defying tree against the pale
morning sky (the conditions more than the object being significant)
hold something precious, some golden virtue that we must grasp.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">R.H. Barlow and H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The Night Ocean"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1936"><p>
I felt, in brief agonies of disillusionment, the gigantic blackness of
this overwhelming universe, in  which my days and the days of my race
were as nothing to the shattered stars; a universe in which each
action is vain and even the emotion of grief a wasted thing.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">R.H. Barlow and H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"The Night Ocean"</source>
</quotation>


<!-- Nonfiction -->

<quotation date="1921"><p>
   It is easy to remove the mind from harping on the lost
   illusion of immortality. The disciplined intellect fears nothing and
   craves no sugar-plum at the day's end, but is content to accept life
   and serve society as best it may. Personally I would not care for
   immortality in the least. There is nothing better than oblivion, since
   in oblivion there is no wish unfulfilled. We had it before we were
   born, yet did not complain. Shall we whine because we know it will
   return? It is Elysium enough for me, at any rate.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"In Defence of Dagon"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1927"><p>
The oldest and strongest emotion of mankind is fear, and the oldest
and strongest kind of fear is fear of the unknown.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
    <source>"Supernatural Horror in Literature"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1927"><p>
The appeal of the spectrally macabre is generally narrow because it
demands from the reader a certain degree of imagination and a capacity
for detachment from every-day life.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"Supernatural Horror in Literature"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1927"><p>
Children will always be afraid of the dark, and men with minds
sensitive to hereditary impulse will always tremble at the thought of
the hidden and fathomless worlds of strange life which may pulsate in
the gulfs beyond the stars, or press hideously upon our own globe in
unholy dimensions which only the dead and the moonstruck can glimpse.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"Supernatural Horror in Literature"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1927"><p>
Creative minds are uneven, and the best of fabrics have their dull spots.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"Supernatural Horror in Literature"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1927"><p>
The true weird tale has something more than secret murder,
bloody bones, or a sheeted form clanking chains according to rule.  A
certain atmosphere of breathless and unexplainable dread of outer,
unknown forces must be present, and there must be a hint, expressed
with a seriousness and portentousness becoming its subject, of that
most terrible conception of the human brain -- a malign and particular
suspension or defeat of those fixed laws of Nature which are our only
safeguard against the assaults of chaos and the daemons of unplumbed
space.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
    <source>"Supernatural Horror in Literature"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1927"><p>
The one test of the really weird is simply this -- whether or not
there be excited in the reader a profound sense of dread, and of
contact with unknown spheres and powers; a subtle attitude of awed
listening, as if for the beating of black wings or the scratching of
outside shapes and entities on the known universe's utmost rim.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"Supernatural Horror in Literature"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1927"><p>
Yet who shall declare the dark theme a positive handicap?  Radiant
with beauty, the Cup of the Ptolemies was carven of onyx.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"Supernatural Horror in Literature"</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1914-09-05"><p>
It is an unfortunate fact that every man who seeks to disseminate
knowledge must contend not only against ignorance itself, but against
false instruction as well. No sooner do we deem ourselves free from a
particularly gross superstition, than we are confronted by some enemy
to learning who would set aside all the intellectual progress of
years, and plunge us back into the darkness of mediaeval disbelief.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
    <source>In a letter to the Providence Evening News, September 5 1914</source>
</quotation>


<!-- Letters: From volume I of the "Selected Letters" -->

<quotation date="1924"><p>
Round pegs find round holes, square pegs find square holes.  And by
the same token, albeit with rather greater difficulty, I am sure that
there must somewhere be a corresponding hole for such a peg as
proverbial metaphor may dub trapezohedral!
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter applying for a job</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1915-09-30"><p>
As, gazing on each comic act / I stare at your perfection, /
I find it hard to face the fact / That you're a mere projection.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>"To Charlie of the Comics", in a letter to Reinhardt
  Kleiner, September 30 1915
</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1916"><p>
Frankly, I cannot conceive how any thoughtful man can really be
happy.  There is really nothing in the universe to live for, and
unless one can dismiss thought and speculation from his mind, he is
liable to be engulfed by the very immensity of creation.  It is vastly
better that he should amuse himself with religion, or any other
convenient palliative to reality which comes to hand.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Kleiner, Cole, and Moe, October 1916</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1918-02-03"><p>
I am no great success in this world, and doubtless will not be in the
next, but when it comes to a catalogue of crimes and evils I really
cannot think of any worse offense than writing bad verse and not
rolling my "rrr...s".
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Maurice W. Moe, February 3 1918</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1918-05-15"><p>
Foolish, do I hear you say?  Undoubtedly!  I had better be a
consistent pragmatist: get drunk and confine myself to a happy,
swinish, contented little world -- the gutter -- till some policeman's
No. 13 boot intrudes upon my philosophic repose.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Maurice W. Moe, May 15 1918</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1918-05-27"><p>
As to "Sherlock Holmes" -- I used to be infatuated with him!  I read 
every Sherlock Holmes story published, and even organised a detective
agency when I was thirteen, arrogating to myself the proud pseudonym
of S.H. ...
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Alfred Galpin, May 27 1918</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1918-05-27"><p>
About the word "peruse" -- possibly I do employ it to excess, but 
Mr Addison was ever my model of style in prose.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Alfred Galpin, May 27 1918</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1919-03-19"><p>
My mother, showing no signs of recovery, has gone to a hospital, where
she is receiving the most expert care which medical science can
afford.  I strongly hope the change will benefit her.  It has a good
chance of doing so, since many features of diet &amp; regimen which
the physicians are prescribing, are directly opposite to those
prescribed by the previous practitioner.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Reinhardt Kleiner, March 19 1919</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1919-09-27"><p>
Of course, I am unfamiliar with amatory phenomena save through cursory
reading.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Reinhardt Kleiner, September 27 1919</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
Then I perceived with horror that I was growing too old for pleasure.
Ruthless Time had set its fell claw upon me, and I was seventeen.  Big
boys do not play in toy houses and mock gardens, so I was obliged to
turn over my world in sorrow to another and younger boy who dwelt
across the lot from me.  And since that time I have not delved in the
earth or laid out paths and roads.  There is too much wistful memory
in such procedure, for the fleeting joy of childhood may never be
recaptured.  Adulthood is hell.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to the Gallomo (Galpin, Lovecraft, and Moe), 1920</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1920-03-07"><p>
I was 23 years of age, and realised that my infirmities would withhold
me from success in the world at large.  Feeling like a cipher, 
I felt that I might well be erased.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Reinhardt Kleiner, March 7 1920</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1920-05-21"><p>
I had a visitor the other night, who gave me an idea for a good story.
He was a furry, four-footed young visitor, with a black coat, white
gloves and boots, and white around the tip of his nose and the tip of
his tail.  He sat in a chair near me, purring most inspiringly, when I
permitted my fancy to consider his ancient race and heritage.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Reinhardt Kleiner, May 21 1920</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
They invited me to their meeting of March 10, which was supposed to be 
in honour of the not unknown Santus Patricius -- the Scotsman who
drave from Hibernia all the snakes save the Sinn Fein.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Reinhardt Kleiner, April 23 1921</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
I expect nothing of man, and disown the race.  The only folly is
expecting what is never attained; man is most contemptible when
compared with his own pretensions.  It is better to laugh at man from
outside the universe, than to weep for him within.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Reinhardt Kleiner, April 23 1921</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
Anything savouring of quiet and tameness is maddeningly abhorrent to
me -- not in actual life,
for that I wish as placid as possible; but in thought, which is my
more vivid life.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Reinhardt Kleiner, May 13 1921</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
I shall never be very merry or very sad, for I am more prone to
analyse than to feel.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Reinhardt Kleiner, May 13 1921</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
What merriment I have is always derived from
the satirical principle, and what sadness I have, is not so much
personal, as a vast and terrible melancholy at the pain and futility
of all existence in a blind and purposeless cosmos.  
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Reinhardt Kleiner, May 13 1921</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
When Kleiner showed me the sky-line of New York I told him that man is
like the coral insect -- designed to build vast, beautiful, mineral
things for the moon to delight in
after he is dead.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Frank Belknap Long, May 3 1922</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
David V. Bush is a short, plump fellow of about forty-five, with a
bland face, bald head, and very fair taste in attire.  He is actually
an immensely good sort -- kindly, affable, winning, and smiling.
Probably he has to be in order to induce people to let him live after
they have read his verse.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Anne Tillery Renshaw, June 14 1922</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
With becoming modesty he announces his intention of revolutionising
the country with his new gospel of dynamic psychology; which has all
the virtues of "New Thought" plus a saving vagueness which prevents
its absurdity from being exposed before the credulous public amongst
whom his missionary labours lie.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Anne Tillery Renshaw, June 14 1922</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
He enjoys life --
as do all who are spared the curse of intelligence.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Anne Tillery Renshaw, June 14 1922</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
I'm now too thoroughly cynical to expect much of amateurdom, or to
give many damns about it; save as a perpetually chaotic mess from
which a few odd souls can get some impetus toward literary development
... or at least toward a fairly comfortable literary disillusion.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to James F. Morton, April 22 1923</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
Physical life and experience, with the narrowings of artistic vision
they create in the majority, are the objects of my most profoud
contempt.  It is for this reason that I despise Bohemians, who think
it essential to art to lead wild lives.  My loathing is not from the
standpoint of Puritan morality, but from that of aesthetic
independence -- I revolt at the notion that physical life is of any value or
significance.
To me the ideal artist is a gentleman who shows his contempt for life
by continuing in the quiet ways of his ancestors, leaving his fancy
free to explore refulgent and amazing spheres.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Frank Belknap Long, May 13 1923</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
Ideas are very foolish -- they mean nothing and lead nowhere.
Rest, beauty, tranquility -- these only have value.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Frank Belknap Long, May 26 1923</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
I have no opinions -- I believe in nothing -- but assume
for the time whatever opinion amuses me or is opposite to that of the
person or persons present.  
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to James F. Morton, May 26 1923</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
Evening had come, and through silent, unillumined Colonial streets I
made my way to the station, glancing now and then at the arabesques of
the tenebrous steeples and Gothic vanes and singular chimney-pots as
they stood limned before the inscrutable and immemorial stars; the
pale, langurous stars that saw Portsmouth born, and that without a
smile will see Portsmouth die.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Maurice W. Moe, September 4 1923</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
I am lately inform'd that, all these weeks later, young Donald's first
remark on being introduc'd to Niagara Falls, was the exclamation:
"Gee, what wou'd Mr. Lovecraft say!" -- a thing which may be taken as
evidence, that the youth is not unimprest with volubility and flow,
whether in aqueous torrents or in childish old gentlemen.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Frank Belknap Long, September 4 1923</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
I hated monstrously to see him go, for he is a person of the most
companionable amiability, even if he does write down all his
expenditures in a little green note book for his wife to see.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Frank Belknap Long, September 4 1923</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
As to these limited editions and so forth --
I don't care for 'em at all.  All I want of a book is to have it in
good clear type for my old eyes, clean, and free from misprints.  What
edition it is, or who owned it in the past, isn't any concern of mine;
although I do like it to be in the "long S" if possible.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Frank Belknap Long, October 7 1923</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
Nothing matters, but it's perhaps more comfortable to keep calm and
not interfere with other people.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Frank Belknap Long, October 7 1923</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
I was only fifteen minutes late -- 
a degree of promptness which will through all my after life give me 
the sensation of being as punctual as a tradesman.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Samuel Loveman, January 5 1924</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
We ascended to the organ loft, and I endeavor'd to play 
<cite>Yes, We Have no Bananas</cite>, but was balk'd by lack of power,
since
the machine is not a self-starter.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Samuel Loveman, January 5 1924</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
I have always thought there is a peculiar fascination about provincial
towns, where time treads lightly and leaves curious byways, customs,
and heritages; all the more fascinating if the town be large enough to
contain bewildering and labyrinthine recesses, and little worlds
unknown each to the other.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Frank Belknap Long, January 8 1924</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
Habitations of men should never be <em>made</em> -- they should 
be sown, water'd, weeded, tended, and allowed to <em>grow</em> by
subtle processes.  What makes a town really lovely and fascinating, is
the quaint irregularity which links it to its geographical location -- 
the suggestions of hill and dale, river and shore -- and to
the continuous history of its inhabitants -- the marks of original
settlement, slow expansion, and development in channels and directions
determin'd by the topography of the site and aspirations and genius of
the people.  These things are all that make a city vivid and dramatick
and human -- all that give it  the captivating individuality which
differentiates it from any other city.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Frank Belknap Long, January 26 1924</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
Happy indeed is that town which grew slowly enough to leave traces of
the gradual evolution from year to year, and gently enough to preserve
the original topographical lines of hill and shore --
the lines that are graceful because born of Nature, and that find
embodiment in curved streets, quaint slopes or flights of steps,
simple and dignify'd bridges, sea-walls, and embankments, quiet nooks
and terraces, and all other vestiges which show man's conformity to
Nature rather than man's artificial conquest of Nature by prosaic,
repudiatory feats of engineering.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Frank Belknap Long, January 26 1924</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
If these ancient spots were fascinating in the busy hours of twilight,
fancy their utter and poignant charm in the sinister hours before
dawn, when only cats, criminals, astronomers, and poetic antiquarians
roam the waking world!
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Mrs F.C. Clark, September 29-30 1924</source>
</quotation>


<!-- Letters: From volume II of the "Selected Letters" -->

<quotation><p>The town, brooding quietly in the Sabbath radiance
  despite the herds of sightseers unloos'd upon it, does not at first
  impress one.  The Monument is so distant, the sky so vacant of tall
  buildings, and the ground so devoted to parks, malls, and wide
  spaces, that one cannot gather the sense of compact and active life
  which one usually associates with large cities.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>Describing Washington DC, in a letter to Mrs F.C. Clark,
  April 21 1925</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
During this hospital period I had my first experience in lone
housekeeping.  Aided by the written instructions of my wife I made
coffee that I could actually drink, and cooked spaghetti that I could
actually eat -- and as a matter of personal pride I kept the house
swept and dusted.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Maurice W. Moe, June 15 1925</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
Reaching the farmhouse by motor from the station, 
we found it quite tolerable though somewhat lonely; 
and to my mind vastly enhanced by the lively presence
of a large family of irresistible gray kittens.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Maurice W. Moe, June 15 1925</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
I like a tale to be told as directly and impersonally as possible,
from an angle of utter and absolute detachment.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Frank Belknap Long, August 2 1925</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
It so happens that I am unable to take pleasure or interest in
anything but a mental re-creation of other &amp; better days ...
so in order to avoid the madness which leads to violence &amp; suicide 
I must cling to the few shreds of old days &amp; old ways which are
left to me.  
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to an unknown correspondent, August 8 1925</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
Yes -- such sensitivenesses of temperament are very inconvenient when
one has no money -- but it's easier to criticise than to cure them.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to an unknown correspondent, August 8 1925</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
As I have always said, missionaries are infernal nuisances who ought
to be kept at home -- dull, solemn asses without scientific acumen 
or historical perspective ...
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Mrs F.C. Clark, September 12-13 1925</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
When my stuff is done it always disappoints me -- never quite
presenting the fulness of the picture I have in  mind -- but since a
crude fixation of the image is better than nothing, I plug along &amp; do 
the feeble best I can.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Clark Ashton Smith, September 20 1925</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
Peste!  Sacrebleu!  Nom d'un Cochon vert!  
O Saint Dieu et Notre Dame de Montreal!  THIS GAWD-DAMN COLD!!!
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to James F. Morton, November 1925</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
Ineffective &amp; injudicious I may be, but I trust I may never be 
inartistic or ill-bred in my course of conduct.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to an unknown correspondent, December 22-23 1925</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
Possess, O Flambeau of Patersonic Tenebrosity, a cardiac organ; and
heap upon my valueless cranium the carbonaceous symbols of Eblis'
aeternal conflagrations!
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to James F. Morton, January 5 1926</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p> 
Nothing really matters, and the only thing for a person
to do is to take the artificial and traditional values he finds around
him and pretend they are real; in order to retain that illusion of
significance in life which gives to human events their apparent
motivation and semblance of interest.
</p>
  <author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author> 
  <source>In a letter to Walter J. Coates, March 30 1926</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
Yrs. for ghouls, afreets, and undertakers--
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>Sign-off from a letter to Wilfred Blanch Talman, April 23 1926</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
As to Long's notion that your work systematically contains 
phallic symbolism -- he picked that up at second-hand from Loveman,
who seems to have done enough delving in that line to see phalli in
most things from church steeples to mushrooms.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Clark Ashton Smith, May 14 1926</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
  It's a pretty old world, after all, &amp; we shall never learn
much about the inner nature of things...
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Clark Ashton Smith, May 14 1926</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
You poets can't age -- split me, Sir, if Samuelus isn't a flaming
youth still from all his barren pole and uncertain equator!
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Frank Belknap Long, June 1926</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
As to what is meant by "weird" -- and of course weirdness is by no
means confined to horror -- I should say that the real criterion is
<em>a strong impression of the suspension of natural laws or the
presence of unseen worlds or forces close at hand</em>.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Wilfred Blanch Talman, August 24 1926</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
Besides the aesthetic, you have managed to work in the practical --
which is always a sealed mystery to me.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Wilfred Blanch Talman, September 8 1926</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
I imagine that Wandrei must be rather a young chap -- though possessed
of a fund of imagery &amp; command of language which will serve him
well when he has learnt the lessons of restraint &amp; austerity of
form
form which come with later life.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Clark Ashton Smith, October 12 1926</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
I can't get interested in it -- it doesn't even bore me enough to take
my mind off other boredoms.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Frank Belknap Long, October 26 1926</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
This primary attention to plot is probably a wise choice on your part,
because to the weird writer plot is so much more difficult to achieve 
than atmosphere.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Wilfred Blanch Talman, October 31 1926</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
But in the end, atmosphere repays cultivation; because it is the final
criterion of convincingness or unconvincingness in any tale whose
major appeal is to the imagination.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Wilfred Blanch Talman, October 31 1926</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
And to think I read them ----- ----- proofs <em>five</em> ----- ----- times!
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to James F. Morton, November 17 1926</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
As to eyeshades and reversed caps -- you can't convince me that either
or both is or are (a) worth getting indignant or critical about, or (b)
any more foolish than dozens of other accepted customs.  
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to James F. Morton, November 17 1926</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
Everything in the world outside primitive needs is the chance result
of inessential causes and random associations, and there's no real or
solid criterion  by which one can condemn any particular manifestation
of human restlessness.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to James F. Morton, November 17 1926</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
In the more southerly portions the very earth sparkles with some
shining powder that the fanciful would call star dust -- but which I,
as a veteran mineralogist, know must come from the oxydising up of the
neighbouring rocks -- which have mica or something.
Being exceedingly charitable where expense is not involved, I herewith
enclose a very modest specimen as a nucleus of the Theobald Collection
of American Rocks, for which I shall expect a special wing to be
built at the museum.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to James F. Morton, November 26 1926</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
All  we may say is, that the more purely an aesthete a man is, the
more likely he is to prefer cats; since the superior grace, beauty,
manners and neatness of the cat cannot but conquer the fancy of any
impartial observer emancipated from mundane and ethical illusions.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to James F. Morton, December 1926</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
We love kitties, gawd bless their little whiskers, and we don't give a 
damn whether they or we are superior or inferior!  They're confounded
pretty, and that's all we know and all we need to know!
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to James F. Morton, December 1926</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
You can get a fairly good bird's-eye view of literary modernism
by reading Ben Hecht's <cite>Erik Dorn</cite> for prose,
and T.S. Eliot's <cite>The Waste Land</cite> for what purports to be verse.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to August Derleth, January 2 1927</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
About Oscar Wilde -- it seems to me that he forms a prominent point in
the history of literature without having been supremely great himself.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to August Derleth, January 20 1927</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
No -- New York is dead, &amp; the brilliancy which so impresses one
from outside is the phosphoresence of a maggoty corpse.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Donald Wandrei, February 10 1927</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
Sterling was a real poet, &amp; the fact of his not fitting 
the age is purely the age's fault.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Clark Ashton Smith, February 18 1927</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
By this time I see pretty well what I'm driving at and how I'm doing
it -- that I'm a rather one-sided person whose only really burning
interests are <em>the past</em> and <em>the unknown</em> or <em>the
strange</em>, and whose aestheticism in general is more negative than
positive -- i.e., a hatred of ugliness rather than an active love of 
beauty.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Bernard Austin Dwyer, March 3 1927</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
I abhor broad prosaic highways  with their implications of change,
modernity, and decadence, and make for the calm, untainted inner
countryside whenever I possibly can.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Bernard Austin Dwyer, March 3 1927</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
I conceived the idea that the great brownstone house was a malignly
sentient thing -- a dead, vampire creature which sucked something out
of those within it and implanted in them the seeds of some horrible
and immaterial psychic growth.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Bernard Austin Dwyer, March 26 1927</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
It is the frank &amp; cynical recognition of the inevitable
limitations of people in general which makes me absolutely indifferent
instead of actively hostile toward mankind.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Donald Wandrei, March 27 1927</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
If I could create an ideal world, it would be an England with the fire
of the Elizabethans, the correct taste of the Georgians, and the
refinement 
and pure ideals of the Victorians.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to James F. Morton, April 1 1927</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
The vistas I relish most are those in which the sunset plays 
a transfiguring &amp; glorifying part.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Donald Wandrei, April 21 1927</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
Living things -- usually insane or idiotic members of the family --
concealed in the garrets or secret rooms of old houses are or at least
have been literal realities in rural New England -- I was told by
someone
of how he stopped at a lone farmhouse on some errand years ago, and
was nearly frightened out of his wits by the opening of a sliding
panel in the kitchen wall, and the appearance of the most horrible,
dirt-caked, and matted-bearded face he had ever conceived possible to exist!
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Bernard Austin Dwyer, June 1927</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
Mere grotesqueness is very common; sly, malign madness sometimes lurks
around the corner; and berserk, revolting murder under peculiarly
messy  and clumsy conditions is a matter of not infrequent record.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Bernard Austin Dwyer, June 1927</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
All the common,  unadorned things have been thought and said and
repeated a thousand times before.  The dull, prosaic world of usual
feelings and events is so well "written up" that nothing vital remains
to be added.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Zealia Brown Reed, June 5 1927</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
And one may add, that the birth of a dear little chee-ild would
<em>not</em> solve all problems in glib nickleodeon fashion!
Rather, it would be a complication provocative of even more misery.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Zealia Brown Reed, June 12 1927</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
Chambers is like Rupert Hughes &amp; a few other fallen Titans --
equipped with the right brains &amp; education, but wholly out of the
habit of using them.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Clark Ashton Smith, June 24 1927</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
Now all my tales are based on the fundamental premise that common
human laws and interests and emotions have no validity or significance
in the vast cosmos-at-large.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Fransworth Wright, July 5 1927</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
Wandrei can tell you all there is to be told about the art of 
hitch-hiking, whereby the expense of railway fare becomes as obsolete
&amp; quaint a memory as the era of good taste in literature!
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Clark Ashton Smith, July 15 1927</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
There are <em>twenty-eight</em> varieties this season, and we
<em>sampled them all</em> within the course of an hour.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>About ice cream, in a letter to Maurice W. Moe, July 30 1927</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
And now, at thirty-seven, I am gradually headed for pure
antiquarianism 
and architecture, and away from literature altogether!  Heaven knows
where I'll end up -- but it's a safe bet that I'll never be at the top
of anything!  Nor do I particularly care to be.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Zealia Brown Reed, August 28 1927</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
Well, the orgy is over at last, and the Old Gentlemen is weakly
gasping amidst the prodigious  welter of work which piled up during
his absence.  Shall I ever see daylight again?
<!-- should be &amacron; in the next line -->
Only Mana-Yood-Sushai can tell!  I  burrow -- I wallow --
and still there press spectrally upon me the sinister shadows of
imperative agenda.  Where did I mislay that cyanide?  No matter, a
revolver will do.  But first I must get those Bullen proofs out of the way!
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Frank Belknap Long, September 6 1927</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
Of course, so far as personal taste goes, I'm no lover of humanity.  
To me cats are in every way more graceful and worthy of respect -- but
I don't try to raise my personal bias to the spurious dignity of a
dogmatic generality...
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Frank Belknap Long, September 6 1927</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
That is the perennial grief of an architectural antiquarian -- in a
city as large as Providence or Boston something quaint is always being
demolished in the interest of alleged progress...
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Zealia Brown Reed, September 22 1927</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
As for your new novelette -- look here, young man, you'd better be
mighty careful how you treat your aged and dignified Grandpa as here!
You mustn't make me doing anything cheerful or wholesome,
and remember that only the direst of damnations can befit so
inveterate a daemon of the cosmick abysses.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Frank Belknap Long, September 24 1727</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
I haven't very much energy or perseverance -- the uselessness of
everything, including even aesthetic effort, overshadows my
consciousness &amp; co&ouml;perates with my native indolence in
defeating all progressive or constructive developments.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Clark Ashton Smith, October 1 1927</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
As to futility &amp; work -- I have come to the comfortably elderly
condition of not caring a rap whether I do anything or not!
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Clark Ashton Smith, October 15 1927</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
I didn't want the mediaeval stuff, but the book was too good to tear
in half.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>On the purchase of Goodyear's <cite>Roman and Mediaeval
Art</cite>,
in a letter to Frank Belknap Long, November 1927</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
Sir, I refuse to fall into your adroit trap!  I simply say -- with a
delicate wave of a perfectly manicured and correctly gloved hand --
that you are wrong and I am right.  Why?  Because I say so!  And that
is all a gentleman can add to the matter!
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to James F. Morton, November 13 1927</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
In a way, crosswords do harm by cluttering up the mind with an aimless
heap of unusual words selected purely for mechanical exigencies and
having no well-proportioned relation to the needs of graceful discourse.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to James F. Morton, November 17 1927</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
After walking for some distance, I encounter'd the rusty tracks of a
street-railway, &amp; the worm-eaten poles which still held the limp
&amp; sagging trolley wire.
Following this line, I soon came upon a yellow, vestibuled car
numbered 1852 -- of a plain, double-trucked type common from 1900 to
1910.
It was untenanted, but evidently ready to start; the trolley being on
the wire &amp; the air-brake pump now &amp; then throbbing beneath the
floor.
I boarded it &amp; looked vainly about for the light switch -- noting
as I did so the absence of controller handle which implied the brief
absence of the motorman.  Then I sat down in one of the cross seats
toward the middle, awaiting the arrival of the crew &amp; the starting
of the vehicle.  Presently I heard a swishing in the sparse grass
toward the left, &amp; saw the dark forms of two men looming up in the
moonlight.  They had the regulation caps of a railway company, &amp; I
could not doubt but that they were the conductor &amp; motorman.  Then
one of them <em>sniffed</em> with singular sharpness, &amp; raised his
face to howl to the moon.  The other dropped on all fours to run
toward the car.  I leaped up at once &amp; raced madly out of that car
&amp; away across endless leagues of plateau till exhaustion waked me
-- doing this not because the conductor had dropped on all fours, but
because the face of the motorman was a mere white cone tapeding to one
blood-red tentacle. ...
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Donald Wandrei,  November 24 1927, recounting
a dream of the night before</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
In furnishing my Irish colleague with an account of my vivid and
active career I did not think it necessary to mention trifles so tame
as Satanism and neogonophagy -- nay, nor my voyage up the Oxus, nor my
visit to Samarcand, nor how <em>and why</em> I slew the yellow-veiled
priest at Lhasa -- that priest whose yellow silken veil stood out
<em>too far</em> in front of where his face ought to be, and moved in
a manner that <em>I did not like</em>.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Frank Belknap Long, December 1927</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
The Magnum Innominandum does not forget.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Frank Belknap Long, December 1927</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>As for affectation -- I'm not fond of any kind, but hate
  literary affectation the worst, because it is more permanent and
  subversive in its essence.  We can get rid of our personal
  affectations when we begin to see their absurdity, but our literary
  affectations are embalmed in cold print, and have perhaps ruined or
  at least vitiated what might have been our best work.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to August Derleth, early December 1927</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
This especial old bird, according to an anecdote recorded by George
Sterling, parted from Bierce under the dramatic circumstances of
having a can broken over his head!  When I saw his fiction I wondered
why Ambrosius didn't use a crowbar.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>Describing Adolphus de Castro in a letter to Farnsworth Wright, December 22 1927</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>I fear my enthusiasm flags when real work is demanded of me.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Wilfred Blanch Talman, December 28 1927</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
Yes -- nocturnal <em>howling</em> has an element of fearfulness for
me.
I always associate it with lean, dog-faced beings that walk sometimes
on two legs and sometimes on four, and that lope abroad in the night's
small hours.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Bernard Austin Dwyer, January 1928</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
As for the matter of drinking -- I have never tasted intoxicating
liquor, and never intend to; having a strong aesthetic disgust at
anything which blunts or coarsens the delicate natural equipoise of
the evolved human intellect and imagination.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Zealia Brown Reed, February 13 1928</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
I think drink is ugly, and therefore I have nothing to do with it.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Zealia Brown Reed, February 13 1928</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
Have you read <cite>The Castle of Otranto</cite> itself?  If not,
<em>don't</em>!    Let the summary in Railo continue to give you a
"kick", for the original certainly won't!
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Bernard Austin Dwyer, February 14 1928</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
Coleridge represented a fine balance betwixt mind and fancy, and I
like him all the better for not having an excess of sloppy emotion.
The fact that his experience came through books rather than life does
not militate against him, because he had the rare faculty of accepting
the contents of books in an abstract way, as if the material came
directly from life with literary filtration.  Bookishness becomes
tepid and artificial only when one looks <em>at</em> the books instead
of <em>through</em> them.  So long as they are utilized only as
telescopes, and not worshipped for their mechanical selves, they form
very acceptable substitutes for vital experience.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Frank Belknap Long, April 1928</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
Ingenuous Age once more essays to find / A proper Gift for Youth's
sophistick Mind, / Well tho' he know how bootless 'tis to send / Aught
that his own old Head can comprehend.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>Accompanying a volume of Proust sent as a gift to Frank
Belknap Long for Christmas 1928</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
Of Wit and Beauty keeps discreetly chary, / And forfeits Sense to be contemporary.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>Accompanying a volume of Proust sent as a gift to Frank
Belknap Long for Christmas 1928</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
Devoid of Pomp as <em>Woolworth's</em> or <em>McCrory's</em>, / And
cerebral as <em>Vogue</em> or <em>Snappy-Stories</em>.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>Accompanying a volume of Proust sent as a gift to Frank
Belknap Long for Christmas 1928</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
What a man <em>does for pay</em> is of little significance.  What he
<em>is</em>, as a sensitive instrument responsive to the world's
beauty, is everything!
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Maurice W. Moe, January 1929</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
I never ask a man what his business is, for it never interests me.
What I ask him about are his thoughts and dreams.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Maurice W. Moe, January 1929</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
Here are we -- and yonder yawns the universe.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Frank Belknap Long, February 20 1929</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
Speaking of boredom -- why don't you try to accumulate a library which
will furnish you with a solid reserve of intellectual and aesthetic
pabulum?  The expense -- unless you are particular about the
appearance of the books -- is truly next to nothing; for one can
obtain astonishing bargains on the 10-cent and 25-cent counters of
second-hand book shops.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Mr. Harris, February 25 to March 1 1929</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
I couldn't live a week without a private library -- indeed, I'd part
with all my furniture and squat and sleep  on the floor before I'd let
go of the 1500 or so books I possess.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Mr. Harris, February 25 to March 1 1929</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
But the important thing to consider is the prodigious vitality of the
Roman idea.  Rome  was so mighty that it <em>could not fall</em>.  It
had to vanish in a cloud, like so many of the mythical heros of
antiquity,
 and to receive its apotheosis among the stars before men became fully
aware that it had vanished from the earth!
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Mr. Harris, February 25 to March 1 1929</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
I am disillusioned enough to know that no man's opinion on any subject
is worth a damn unless backed up with enough genuine information to
make him really know what he's talking about.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Mr. Harris, February 25 to March 1 1929</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
I can dream a whole cycle of colonial life from merely gazing on a
 tattered old book or almanack with the long 'f'.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Mr. Harris, February 25 to March 1 1929</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
It is a treadmill, squirrel-trap culture -- drugged and frenzied with
the hasheesh  of industrial servitude and material luxury.
It is wholly a material body-culture, and its symbol is the tiled
bathroom and steam radiator rather than the Doric portico and the
temple of philosophy.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Mr. Harris, February 25 to March 1 1929</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
All of my 38 1/2 years show in me, I guess; and so far as my
temperament is concerned, I was born an old man.   
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Mr. Harris, February 25 to March 1 1929</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
However -- I am not quite such a solemn prig as you probably assume
from my letters.  
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Mr. Harris, February 25 to March 1 1929</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
My fiction can't be compared with Poe's or Machen's, but I take no
less pleasure in writing it on that account.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Elizabeth Toldridge, March 8 1929</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
The masters of art are not to 'bow down before', but to enjoy
rationally &amp; with a proper appreciation.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Elizabeth Toldridge, March 8 1929</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
Language, vocabulary, ideas, imagery -- everything succumbed to my one
intense purpose of thinking &amp; dreaming myself back into that world
of periwigs &amp; long s's which for some odd reason seemed to me the
normal world.
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Elizabeth Toldridge, March 8 1929</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
Even when I break away, it is generally only through imitating
something else!  There are my "Poe" pieces &amp; my "Dunsany" pieces
-- but alas -- where are my <em>Lovecraft</em> pieces?
  </p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Elizabeth Toldridge, March 8 1929</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
One thing I'll say for labour; &amp; that is, that it isn't as
offensive as the corresponding mutatory force which now threatens
culture in America.  I refer to the force of <em>business</em> as a
dominating motive in life, &amp; a persistent absorber of the
strongest creative energies of the American people.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Elizabeth Toldridge, June 10 1929</source>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
Bunch together a group of people deliberately chosen for strong
religious feelings, and you have a practical guarantee of dark
morbidities expressed in crime, perversion, and insanity.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Robert E. Howard, October 4 1930</source>
</quotation>

<!-- Letters: From volume III of the "Selected Letters" -->

<quotation date="1930-11-03"><p>... an isolated person requires correspondence as a means of seeing
his ideas as others see them, and thus guarding against the dogmatisms
and extravagances of solitary and uncorrected speculation.  No man can
learn to reason and appraise from a mere perusal of the writing of
others.  If he live not in the world, where he can observe the publick
at first hand and be directed toward solid reality by the force of
conversation and spoken debate, then he must sharpen his
discrimination and regulate his perceptive balance by an equivalent
exchange of ideas in epistolary form.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
<source>In a letter to Frank Belknap Long, 3 Nov 1930</source>
</quotation>

<quotation date="1931-02-27"><p>
  <!--Submitted by Donald Davis-->
The process of delving into the black abyss is to me the keenest form
of fascination...
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Frank Belknap Long, February 27 1931</source>
</quotation>


<!-- Letters: From volume ??? of the "Selected Letters" -->

<quotation date="1931-08-03"><p>
If religion were true, its
   followers would not try to bludgeon their young into an artificial
   conformity; but would merely insist on their unbending quest for
   truth, irrespective of artificial backgrounds or practical
   consequences. With such an honest and inflexible openness to evidence,
   they could not fail to receive any real truth which might be
   manifesting itself around them. The fact that religionists do not
   follow this honourable course, but cheat at their game by invoking
   juvenile quasi-hypnosis, is enough to destroy their pretensions in my
   eyes even if their absurdity were not manifest in every other
   direction.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Maurice W. Moe, August 3 1931</source>
</quotation>

<!-- Letters: From volume IV of the "Selected Letters" -->

<quotation date="1932-09-22"><p>
Despite my tremendous admiration for things like
     Dunsany's Gods of the Mountain and O'Neill's Emperor Jones, I have
     never as yet employed drama as a medium of expression. Probably the
     reason is that in the sort of work I am trying to do human
     characters matter very little.  
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
  <source>In a letter to Harold S. Farnese, September 22 1932</source>
</quotation>


<!-- As yet unsourced -->

<quotation><p>
To the scientist there is the joy in pursuing truth which nearly
counteracts the depressing revelations of truth.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
At night, when the objective world has slunk back into its cavern
   and left dreamers to their own, there come inspirations and
   capabilities impossible at any less magical and quiet hour. No one
   knows whether or not he is a writer unless he has tried writing at
   night.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
</quotation>

<quotation><p>
The world is indeed comic, but the joke is on mankind.
</p><author rdf:resource="http://historical-id.info/person/3915">H.P. Lovecraft</author>
</quotation>

</quotations>

