<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="http://www.amk.ca/qel/qel.css"?>
<quotations
  xmlns="http://www.amk.ca/qel/"
  xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
  xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#">
  <title>Quotations from New Doctor Who</title>
  <editor>A.M. Kuchling</editor>

<!-- ENDQT

  <quotation date=""><p>
    </p>
    <source></source>
  </quotation>

-->

  <!-- 12th Doctor -->

  <quotation date="2015-12-25"><p>
    Carol singers will be criticised.
    </p>
    <source>Sign on the TARDIS door, in "The Husbands of River Song"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation date="2015-12-25"><p>
    "I don't like being sure about things.   One minute you're sure, the
    next, everybody turns into lizards and a piano falls on you."
  </p><p>
    "Piano?"
  </p><p>
    "It's been a long day."
    </p>
    <source>The Doctor and Nardole, in "The Husbands of River Song"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation date="2015-12-25"><p>
    "You don't look much like your pictures."
  </p><p>
    "Well, that's an ongoing problem for me."
    </p>
    <source>The Doctor and River, in "The Husbands of River Song"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation date="2015-12-25"><p>
    I think I'm going to need a bigger flowchart.
    </p>
    <source>The Doctor, in "The Husbands of River Song"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation date="2015-12-25"><p>
    What's that face?  Are you thinking?
    Stop it.  You're a man.  It looks weird!
    </p>
    <source>River, in "The Husbands of River Song"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation date="2015-12-25"><p>
    "Does sarcasm help?"
    </p><p>
    "Wouldn't it be a great universe if it did?"
    </p>
    <source>River and the Doctor, in "The Husbands of River Song"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation date="2015-12-25"><p>
    The man who gave me this was the sort of man who'd know
    exactly how long a diary you were going to need.
    </p>
    <source>River, in "The Husbands of River Song"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation date="2015-12-25"><p>
    The Doctor does not and has never loved me.  I'm not lying.
    </p>
    <source>River, in "The Husbands of River Song"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation date="2015-12-25"><p>
    He's the Doctor.  He doesn't go around falling in love with people.
    And if you think he's anything that small or that ordinary, then
    you haven't the first idea of what you're dealing with.
    </p>
    <source>River, in "The Husbands of River Song"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation date="2015-12-25"><p>
    Well, go on, scan it then!  Go on, why don't you!  Two hearts,
    stupid clothes.  You can't miss him!
    </p>
    <source>River, in "The Husbands of River Song"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation date="2015-12-25"><p>
    God knows where he is right now, but I promise you, he's doing
    whatever the hell he wants, and not giving a damn about me.
    </p>
    <source>River, in "The Husbands of River Song"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation date="2015-12-25"><p>
    When you love the Doctor, it's like loving the stars themselves.
    You don't expect a sunset to admire you back.
    </p>
    <source>River, in "The Husbands of River Song"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation date="2015-12-25"><p>
    "And if I happen to find myself in danger, let me tell you, the Doctor
    is not stupid enough, or sentimental enough, and he is *certainly*
    not in love enough to find himself standing in it with me!"
    </p><p>
    "Hello, Sweetie."
    </p>
    <source>River and the Doctor, in "The Husbands of River Song"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation date="2015-12-25"><p>
    "What do you think, by the way?"
  </p><p>
    "Of what?"
  </p><p>
    "My new body."
  </p><p>
    "Oh, I'll let you know.  I've only seen the face."
    </p>
    <source>The Doctor and River, in "The Husbands of River Song"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation date="2015-12-25"><p>
    Times end, River.  Because they have to.  Because there's no such
    thing as happy ever after. It's just a lie we tell ourselves
    because the truth is so hard.
    </p>
    <source>The Doctor, in "The Husbands of River Song"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation date="2015-12-25"><p>
    They've been there for millions of years.  Through storms and
    floods and wars and time.  Nobody really understands where the
    music comes from.  It's probably something to do with the precise
    positions, the distance between both towers.  Even the locals
    aren't sure.  All anyone will tell you is that when the wind
    stands fair and the night is perfect, when you least expect it,
    but always when you need it the most...  there is a song.
    </p>
    <source>The Doctor, on the Singing Towers of Darillium,
    in "The Husbands of River Song"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation date="2016-12-25"><p>
    "Why do they call him Spider-Man?  Don't they like him?"
  </p><p>
    "He was bitten by a radioactive spider and guess what happened?"
  </p><p>
    "Radiation poisoning, I should think."
    </p>
    <source>The Doctor and Grant as a boy, in "The Return of Doctor Mysterio"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation date="2016-12-25"><p>
    "Where did you get that from?"
  </p><p>
    "My pocket."
  </p><p>
    "How did you put a glass of water in your pocket?"
  </p><p>
    "Skills.  Now, hush. I've got a lot of work to do."
    </p>
    <source>, in "The Return of Doctor Mysterio"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation date="2016-12-25"><p>
    "Who are you?"
      </p><p>
    "There have been many attempts to conquer the Earth.  I've lost count.  Not one of them has succeeded.  Not a single one.  They all lost, and burned, and ran.  That's who I am."
    </p>
    <source>Mr Brock and the Doctor, in "The Return of Doctor Mysterio"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation date="2016-12-25"><p>
    "Where did you get the robes?"
      </p><p>
    "Twelfth century Constantinople. I ruled firmly but wisely."
    </p>
    <source>The Doctor and Nardole, in "The Return of Doctor Mysterio"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation date="2016-12-25"><p>
    "But oh! Look at you, avoiding the subject."
  </p><p>
    "I'm not avoiding anything. I'm just trying to save a planet."
  </p><p>
    "Which is what you always do when the conversation turns serious."
    </p>
    <source>Nardole and the Doctor, in "The Return of Doctor Mysterio"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation date="2016-12-25"><p>
    The thing about being in a room full of buttons and switches is...
    I love buttons and switches!
    </p>
    <source>The Doctor, in "The Return of Doctor Mysterio"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation date="2016-12-25"><p>
    "I mean, life's not a comic book.  Right, Doctor?"
  </p><p>
    "Possibly I'm not the right person to ask."
    </p>
    <source>Grant and the Doctor, in "The Return of Doctor Mysterio"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation date="2016-12-25"><p>
    Things end.  That's all. Everything ends... and it's always sad.
    But everything begins again too, and that's always happy.  Be happy.
    I'll look after everything else.
    </p>
    <source>The Doctor, in "The Return of Doctor Mysterio"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation date="2017-12-25"><p>
    "Have you come to take the ship back"?
    </p><p>
    "The ship?  You still call it 'a ship'!"
    </p>
    <source>Doctor #1 and #12, in "Twice Upon A Time"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation date="2017-12-25"><p>
    I have the courage and the right to live and die as myself.
    </p>
    <source>The First Doctor, in "Twice Upon A Time"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation date="2017-12-25"><p>
    We have a choice.  Either we change and go on... or we die as we are.
    </p>
    <source>dThe Twelfth Doctor, in "Twice Upon A Time"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation date="2017-12-25"><p>
    Does rather make me wish you understood English... or that I spoke German.
    </p>
    <source>The Captain, in "Twice Upon A Time"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation date="2017-12-25"><p>
    "It's bigger on the inside than it is on the outside!"
    </p><p>
    "You know, I thought it probably was. I'm glad it's not just me."
    </p>
    <source>The Captain and the Twelfth Doctor, in "Twice Upon A Time"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation date="2017-12-25"><p>
    Always remember where you parked.  It's going to come up a lot.
    </p>
    <source>The Twelfth Doctor, in "Twice Upon A Time"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation date="2017-12-25"><p>
      "B-But I thought... Well, I, uh, assumed I'd get... younger."
    </p><p>
      "I *am* younger!"
    </p>
    <source>The First and the Twelfth Doctor, in "Twice Upon A Time"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation date="2017-12-25"><p>
     "Wh-What was that?"
   </p>
   "To be fair, they cut out all the jokes."
    <source>The First and the Twelfth Doctor, in "Twice Upon A Time"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation date="2017-12-25"><p>
    "Quite beautiful really, isn't she?"
  </p><p>
    "Yeah, if you like ladies made of glass."
  </p><p>
    "Well, aren't all ladies made of glass, in a way?"
  </p>
    <source>The Captain, Bill, and the First Doctor, in "Twice Upon A Time"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation date="2017-12-25"><p>
    "I don't remember this. Why are you refusing the regeneration?"
  </p><p>
    "Fear.  I am afraid.  Very, very afraid."
    </p>
    <source>The First and the Twelfth Doctor, in "Twice Upon A Time"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation date="2017-12-25"><p>
    "There is good, and there is evil.  I left Gallifrey to answer a question of my own.  By any analysis, evil should always win.  Good is not a practical survival strategy.  It requires loyalty, self-sacrifice, and love.  So, why  does good prevail?  What keeps the balance between good and evil in this appalling universe?  Is there some kind of logic?  Some mysterious force?"
  </p><p>
    "Perhaps there's just a bloke."
    </p>
    <source> The First Doctor and Bill, in "Twice Upon A Time"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation date="2017-12-25"><p>
    Oh.  It's not an evil plan.  I- I don't really know what to do
    when it isn't an evil plan.
    </p>
    <source>The Twelfth Doctor, in "Twice Upon A Time"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation date="2017-12-25"><p>
    I regret, Captain, that the universe generally fails
    to be a fairy tale.
    </p>
    <source>The First Doctor, in "Twice Upon A Time"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation date="2017-12-25"><p>
    I adjusted the time frame, only by a couple of hours.  Any other
    day, it wouldn't make any difference.  but this is Christmas 1914
    and the human miracle is about to happen.  The Christmas
    armistice...
    It never happened again.  Any war, anywhere.  But for one day, one
    Christmas, a very long time ago, everyone just put down their
    weapons and started to sing.  Everybody just stopped.
    Everyone... was just kind.
    </p>
    <source>The Twelfth Doctor, in "Twice Upon A Time"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation date="2017-12-25"><p>
    You were right, you know?  The universe generally fails to be a fairy tale.  But that's where we come in.
    </p>
    <source>The Twelfth Doctor, in "Twice Upon A Time"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation date="2017-12-25"><p>"You know what the hardest thing about knowing you was?"
  </p><p>
    "My superior intelligence?  My dazzling charisma?  Oh, my impeccable dress sense."
  </p><p>
    "Letting you go.  Letting go of the Doctor is so, so hard, isn't it?"
    </p>
    <source>Bill and the Twelfth Doctor, in "Twice Upon A Time"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation date="2017-12-25"><p>
    You're just memories, held in glass.  Do you know how many of you I could fill?  I
    would shatter you.
    My testimony would shatter all of you.
    </p>
    <source>The Twelfth Doctor, in "Twice Upon A Time"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation date="2017-12-25"><p>
    A life this long -- do you understand what it is?  It's a battlefield, like this one. &lt;gestures&gt;  And it's empty.  Because everyone else has fallen.
    </p>
    <source>The Twelfth Doctor, in "Twice Upon A Time"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation date="2017-12-25"><p>
     Time to leave the battlefield.
    </p>
    <source>The Twelfth Doctor, in "Twice Upon A Time"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation date="2017-12-25"><p>
    Well, I suppose... one more lifetime won't kill anyone.  Well, except me.        </p>
    <source>The Twelfth Doctor, in "Twice Upon A Time"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation date="2017-12-25"><p>
    I've got a few things to say to you.
    Basic stuff first.  Never be cruel, never be cowardly.
    And never, ever eat pears.
    </p>
    <source>The Twelfth Doctor, in "Twice Upon A Time"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation date="2017-12-25"><p>
    Laugh hard.    Run fast.    Be kind.
    </p>
    <source>The Twelfth Doctor, in "Twice Upon A Time"</source>
  </quotation>

  <quotation date="2017-12-25"><p>
    Doctor, I let you go.
    </p>
    <source>Last words of the Twelfth Doctor, in "Twice Upon A Time"</source>
  </quotation>


  <!-- 13th Doctor -->

  <quotation date="2017-12-25"><p>Oh, brilliant!</p>
    <source>First words of the Thirteenth Doctor, in "Twice Upon A Time"</source>
  </quotation>

</quotations>
